<hour>
    <info><hourName>Other Prayers</hourName>
    <description>A collection of prayers that are read in their applicable time
    </description></info>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Prayer Before Holy Communion</title>
		<content>بارب إنى غير مستحق أن تدخل تحت سقف بيتى لأنى إنسان خاطئ فقل كلمه أولآ لتبرأ نفسى.
قل لنفسى مغفورة لك
خطاياك. إنى مقفر وخال من كل صلاح وليس لى سوى تحننك ورأفتك ومحبتك للبشر وأنت قد تنازلت من سماء مجدك 
غير المدرك إلى ذلنا وارتضيت أن تولد فى مذود البقر. فلا ترفض يا مخلصى القدوس أن تقبل إلى نفسى الذليله
الحقيرة التى تنتظر حضورك البهى. إنك لم تستنكف من دخول بيت الأبرص لتشفيه فاسمح يالهى بالدخول إلى نفسى
لتطهرها. لم تمنع الخاطئهٌ من تقبيل قدميك فلا تحرمنى الدنو منك لتناول جسدك الطاهر ودمك الاقدس, بل
فليصر تناولى للإشتراك معك ولإبادة كل ما هو دنس ولإماته ٌأهوائى الدنيئه وللعمل بوصاياك المحييهٌ
ولشفاء نفسى وجسدى من كل خطيهٌ ولقبول مواهبك ولسكنى نعمتك ولحلول روحك وللإتحاد بك والثبات فيك لأحيا
لمجد اسمك القدوس. آمين.
		</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer After Holy Communion</title>
		<content>أشكر صلاحك أيها الآب محب البشر لأنك لم تشأ هلاكى. بل أيقظتنى من غفلتى وهديتنى إلى
طريقك. ورددتنى من وادى 
الهلاك إلى حمى حصنك الأمين. فاملأنى بالرجاء والإيمان. أقبلت إليك يارب كالمريض إلى الطبيب الشافى, و
كالمفتقر 
الجائع إلى الغذاء المشبع, وكالعطشان إلى ينابيع المياة الحيه, وكالفقير إلى مصدر الغنى, وكالخاطئ إلى
المخلص, وكالمائت إلى ينبوع الحياة. لأنك خلاصى, وطبيبى,وقوتى, وتعزيتى, وسعادتى, وفيك راحتى. فأعنى
واحفظنى وسيج حولى. وعلمنى أن أضع بين يديك كل إرادتى. لأسير حسب ما تشاء, أعن ضعفى كى أثبت ودوم أمينا
لك إلى النهايهٌ.
</content>
	</prayer>


    <prayer>
		<title>Prayer of Repentance</title>         
		<content>ربى والهى ومخلصى يسوع المسيح. كنز الرحمة ونبع الخلاص. اتى اليك مقرا بذنوبى.اعترف
بأنى بوقاحه تجاسرت  
ودنست  هيكلك  المقدس  بخطاياى. والان الجاء الى رحمتك وتحننك . لان مراحمك لاتحصى. وانك لا ترد خاطئا
اقبل 
الىك فها انا يارب  معترفا بأن  اثامى قد طمت فوق رأ سى كحمل ثقيل. وقد فارقتنى قوتى. فلاتحجب يارب وجهك
عنى 
لئلا ارتاع. ولا تحاكمنى بحسب استحقاقى. ارحمنى يارب فاءنى ضعيف. اذكر يارب انى عمل يديك وارأف بى.
لاتدخل فى المحاكمه مع عبدك لأنه لن يتبرر قدامك حى. عد وألبسنى حله جديدة تليق لمجدك. اغفر لى وسامحنى 
لأترنم قائلأ:طوبى لمن غفر خطيته. اعترف لك بخطيتى ولا اكتم إثمى . قلت للرب بذنبى. وأنك رفعت آثام
خطيتى. آمىن.
</content>
	</prayer> 
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer Before Confession</title>         
		<content>ايها الآب القدوس , الذى يحب رجوع الخطاة . وقد وعدت انك مستعد لقبولهم. انظر يارب
الآن الى نفس خاطئه قد ضلت 
وتاهت فى اوديه العصيان زمانا طويلآ . فيه تمررت وشعرت بشقاوتها, تطلب منك تطهيرها من الأدناس والأقذار
التى 
توحلت فىها. إقبلها ولا ترقضها فإنك إن نظرت إليها بحنوك وعاملتها برحمتك تنقت وخلصت, وإن أهملتها بادت
وهلكت.
إمنحنى يارب نعمهٌ بها أتقوى على الدنو منك بإيمان وطيد ورجاء تام. لأعترف بذنوبى وأكره العودة إليها.
وليبكتنى روحك على آثامى. أنر قلبى لأرى كم أخطأت وأسأت وتركت وأهملت. وامنحنى عزما على عدم الرجوع إلى
الإثم لأثبت فى حفظ وصاياك وأحيا لمجد اسمك القدوس. آمين.</content>
	</prayer> 

	<prayer>
	      <title>Prayer After Confession</title>         
		<content>أشكر صلاحك أيها الآب محب البشر لأنك لم تشأ هلاكى. بل أيقظتنى من غفلتى وهديتنى إلى
طريقك. ورددتنى من وادى 
الهلاك إلى حمى حصنك الأمين. فاملأنى بالرجاء والإيمان. أقبلت إليك يارب كالمريض إلى الطبيب الشافى, و
كالمفتقر 
الجائع إلى الغذاء المشبع, وكالعطشان إلى ينابيع المياة الحيه, وكالفقير إلى مصدر الغنى, وكالخاطئ إلى
المخلص, وكالمائت إلى ينبوع الحياة. لأنك خلاصى, وطبيبى,وقوتى, وتعزيتى, وسعادتى, وفيك راحتى. فأعنى
واحفظنى وسيج حولى. وعلمنى أن أضع بين يديك كل إرادتى. لأسير حسب ما تشاء, أعن ضعفى كى أثبت ودوم أمينا
لك إلى النهايهٌ.
		</content>
	</prayer> 
	


	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer Before Meals</title>         
		<content>تباركت يارب يا من تعولنا منذ حداثتنا وتهبنا خيراتك. وتهيئ الغذاء للجميع. لأن اعين
الكل تترجاك وأنت تعطيهم طعامهم فى حينه. تفتح يدك فتشبع كل حى رضى. لك المجد والتسبيح والبركه والشكر
على كل ما أعددت لنا من الطعام الموضوع 
على هذه المائدة المعدة لغذاء أجسادنا. إجعله شفاءً وقوةً لحياتنا الجسديه. إمنح خلاصاً ونعمةً وبركةً
وطهراً لكل المتناولين 
منه. إرفع عقولنا إليك كل حين لطلب طعامنا الروحى غير البائد.أعطنا أن نعملْ للطعام الباقى للحـياة
الأبـدية وهبْ لنا
نصيباً فى الإشتراك فى وليمتك السمائية. إمنحنا خبز البركة وكأس الخلاص واملأ قلوبنا من البهجة والفرح.
أنْعمْ علينا بحياة مطمئنة هادئة, وسعادة فى النفس وصحة فى الجسد. علمنا أنْ نطلب رضاك فى كُل شئ حتى
إذا أكلنا أو شربْنا أو عملنا أى شئ حتى إذا أكلنا أو شربْنا أو عملْنا أى شئ نعملهُ لمجد اسْمك القُدوس
لأن لك المجدُ إلى الأبد. آمين.
		</content>
	</prayer> 
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer for God’s Guidance</title>         
		<content>إلهى أنت تعْلمُ أنى لا أعْرف ما هو الصالح لنفْس. وها أنا قد شرعْتُ فى. . . . . فمن
أين لى أن أعْرف حسناً ما هو المفيدُ لى  إن لم أسترشدْ نعمتك فى ذلك. فأسْألُك ياربً أن تدبرنى فى هذا
الأمرُ. لاتتْركنى ومشورة نفسى, ولا تدعْنى أجْرى وراء أمْيالى لئلا اتورط وأسقطُ, بل اعْصم عبدك من
الزلل, وكُنْ مُتكلى وعونْى, ودبر الأمْر بحسب إرادتك كما يُوافقُ صلاحك وإنْ حسْن لديْك فليكنْ كما
تُريد, وهبْنى نعْمتك لأتممهُ, وإن كان يُضر فانْزعْ منى ياربً هذه الرغْبةُ لأنك عليم بكُل شئ ولا
يخْفى عليك أمْر. وها أنا عبدك عاملْنى بما يُوافقُك, إذ لانجاح تام ولا سلام كامل إلا بتسليم ذاتى تحت
تدبير مشيئتك. علمنى أنْ أقول فى كُل شئ : يا أبتاه ليس كمشيئتى بل كمشيئتك. لأن لْك الُملكُ والقُوةُ
والمجدُ من الآن وإلى الأبد. آمين.
		</content>
	</prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>The Priest's Absolution</title>
		<content>We thank and entreat You, O Master and Lord Jesus Christ the Son of the
            Living God, the Eternal, abiding in the light before all ages, Light out of
            Light; enlighten, O Lord, our minds and our hearts, and illuminate our
            understanding, so that we understand Your life-giving words. Raise us from the
            darkness of sin which kills the soul. Make us worthy to be steadfast in good and
            beneficial works. At the time of Your awesome second coming, when you will judge
            the world, may we be worthy of hearing that voice which is full of happiness,
            joy, consolation, delight and grace from Your divine mouth, saying: “Come to Me,
            you blessed of My Father, inherit the kingdom which was prepared for you since
            the creation of the world”. Yes, O Lord our God, fit us to be, on that day and
            in that hour, without fear, without fault, without disturbance, without failure
            and without deviation. Do not deal with us O Lord according to the multitude of
            our sins. Pardon O Lord, all our vices, faults, mistakes and lapses. Relieve us,
            and the whole world, O Lord, from death, inflation, plagues, destruction,
            eviction, the sword of enemies, the plots of demons, the danger of fire and
            drowning, the opposition of those who are evil, the intrigues of the shameless
            and the injustice of judges. Bring to failure the works of the stubborn against
            us. For You are our Lord and God, have compassion on us. Do not cast us into the
            sea of destruction nor to the punishment of our ways. But rescue us, protect us,
            preserve us and raise us from boredom, anger, languishing, and laziness. Do not
            let the enemy - the devil - overwhelm us with excessive hope, but alert our
            minds and awaken our hearts from the sleep of inattention and wasting our
            lifetime in vain. O God, disregard our trespasses and forgive us our lapses, do
            not remember our sins or our vices, do not be angry with us and may Your anger
            not continue forever. Have mercy on us O Lord, have mercy on us, for we are weak
            and poor, drowning in the ocean of sin. Unto You we cry out; before You we bow;
            by You we confess; it is You whom we want. Do not cut off our hope my Master, in
            Your mercy, and do not close the door of Your mercy in our faces. But out of
            Your goodness save us; lead us to Your mercy, and let us hear Your joyful voice.
            O God, purify us and purify our hearts from wicked, unclean and bad thoughts.
            Remove from us, O Lord, and from Your people, all dreams, fancies and devilish
            ideas. Raise us O God, from every fall and catastrophe. Establish in us O God,
            patience, hope, love and orthodox faith. Count us among the sheep at Your right
            hand. Seat us with those who recline in Your heavenly banquet. Forgive us for
            every trespass, guilt and sin; protect us in the fortress of Your luminous,
            angelic soldiers. For we have no salvation except through Your mercy. Our
            reliance is on You, our faith is in You and our hope is in You. Accept from us O
            Lord, our supplications at this present time and at all times. And all those who
            asked and directed us to remember them in prayers, liturgies, unctions of the
            sick and commemorations; whether alive or dead; remember us O Lord, together
            with them, with kindness in the heavenly Jerusalem, in the Kingdom of Heaven.
            Blot out O Lord, our vices, and those who offended us, forgive them and us.
            Through Your mercy O Lord, save all our souls. O Lord, save Your people, bless
            Your inheritance, shepherd and guide them forever. Save those who are in
            hardships, distresses and sadness. Free those who are bound from the bonds of
            devils. Satisfy the hungry with good things. Console the small in heart and
            spirit. Raise the fallen; make steadfast those who have risen. Restore the lost.
            Take care of the widow and the orphan. Aid the needy. Give blessings to the
            fruits of the earth, grant that the weather be favourable, give growth to the
            plants, raise the waters of the rivers fully and bless the dew and the rains.
            Give contentment to those in need. Repay for those in debt. Gather together the
            fragments which are divided. Accept the repentance of the penitent. Accept the
            confession of the confessors. Give understanding to the catechumens. Give fair
            judgment O Lord, to the oppressed. Fill our hearts with joy, happiness, comfort,
            delight and grace, so that as we have sufficiency in all things, we excel in
            acceptable good works. Bless O Lord, the crops with heavenly blessings. Bless O
            Lord the crown of this year with Your goodness. Bless O Lord the sower, the
            cultivator, the planter and the reaper, as You blessed the crops of the children
            of Israel in the sixth year. Bless O Lord this gathering of ours, and all the
            gatherings of orthodox people. Preserve for us the life and the reign of our
            father and Patriarch Pope ..., the Patriarch of this time. Save him O Lord and
            save his people from all catastrophes, trials and sorrows. And also his partners
            in the apostolic ministry, our fathers the Metropolitans, our fathers the
            Bishops, our fathers the Hegumens and our fathers the Priests, our brothers the
            Deacons, our fathers the Monks, our brothers the laymen and those who came,
            attended and shared with us in this prayer and all the prayers of the orthodox,
            now asking for the forgiveness of their sins and mercy for their souls. Bless us
            and bless them; absolve us and absolve them; forgive our sins and their sins,
            those passed and those we might return to, those personal and those not
            personal, those by night ~d those by day, those manifest and those hidden.
            Preserve O Lord, the welfare of the assemblies, the holy churches, the orthodox
            wilderness, and the elders who dwell in them, its servants, its overseers, and
            those who are in it. Grant security, peace, love and reassurance to be among
            them. Bring down the evil enemy under our feet and their feet. Do not let him
            have any part in us or in them, neither by the left hand blow nor by the right
            hand blow, but preserve them with Your exalted hand and Your protective arm.
            Rescue us my Master, from evil temptations and from the snares set, the visible
            and the invisible. Remember O Lord, our fathers, our mothers, our brothers and
            our sisters, our families, our relatives, our teachers, our spiritual children,
            our children in the flesh and all the children of Baptism together. Remember O
            Lord, those through whose toil and effort we have eaten and drunk, have
            sheltered us in their houses and gave us from their hands. Repay them O Lord and
            compensate them with the eternal for the temporal and the heavenly for the
            earthly. Fill their houses and their stores with every good thing. Repay them O
            Lord, thirty fold, sixty fold and a hundredfold, and the forgiveness of their
            sins in the Kingdom of Heaven. Remember O Lord, those who have done good unto us
            and to our poor brethren, with every kind of good work, in love for You and
            honour for Your Holy Name, and bless them. Remember O Lord, those who are
            concerned with the sacrifices, offerings, burnt offerings, wine, oil, first
            fruits, incense, curtains, vows, books of readings and all the utensils of the
            altar generally. Repay them O Lord, for what they have given, with the
            forgiveness of their sins. Grant them in this present age a pleasant life and in
            the coming age eternal life. Remember O Lord our fathers and brethren who have
            departed, reposed and rested with faith in Christ. Repose O Lord, all their
            souls, in the embrace of our holy fathers, Abraham, Isaac and Jacob, in the
            place of the living, in the Paradise of Joy. As for us who are still alive, aid
            us to find salvation for our souls, arrange our lives according to Your gracious
            will. Please O Lord, remember my insignificance, my humiliation, my weakness, I
            the sinner who am troubled, and unworthy of standing between Your hands. Because
            of the multitude of my sins and guilt, do not reject me. Erect O Lord, a horn of
            salvation for Your people through the sign of Your life-giving Cross. We ask
            Your relief in hardships and Your aid in misery and humiliation. Save us O Lord
            and save everyone in hardships. Those of Your people who are sick, heal them.
            Grant O Lord, Your people the Christians, those present with us and those absent
            from us, that they may be blessed and absolved from Your Divine mouth, from the
            rising of the to its setting, and from the north to the south. Accept us unto
            You, as You accepted the right-hand thief when You were on the Cross, and
            granted him the Paradise of Joy. Remember O Lord, the orphans and the widows,
            the estranged, the disabled and those who have no one to remember them. Remember
            us O Lord, with them, in the heavenly Jerusalem. Remember O Lord those standing
            or sitting, sleeping or lying in illness, those who are travelling by land, sea,
            air, on plains, by rough roads, through valleys, narrow ways, on mountain peaks
            and hills, in caves, those who are in gaols or prisons, those who are in
            captivity and exiled, the captives and those who are bound with the bonds of
            wicked powers and of demons. Return them and bring them all to their ports
            safely, profitably and healthy in soul, body and spirit. Grant O my Lord Jesus
            Christ, that these our prayers may be accepted before You without hypocrisy,
            pride, haughtiness, being puffed up or any fault. Aid us O God in doing Your
            will. Aid us in performing Your commandments. Aid us in the pangs of death, and
            that which is before death and that which is after death. For You are a
            righteous God, long suffering, plenteous in mercy and compassion. O Lord grant
            that the door of Your Church be open before us through the ages of ages and unto
            the end of time. Have mercy upon us O God, according to the multitude of Your
            mercy. Through the intercessions of the Lady of intercession, the essence of
            purity, generosity and blessings; our Lady and the pride of our race, the chaste
            Virgin, the blameless St Mary, and the honoured martyr, St Mark the evangelist,
            apostle and preacher of the land of Egypt, and all the angels, the fathers, the
            prophets, the apostles, the martyrs, the saints, the spiritborne, the
            worshipers, the ascetics, the strivers and those who have pleased the Lord with
            their good works, from Adam, to the end of ages. To You, we bow down O Holy
            Trinity, Father, Son and Holy Spirit, now and at all times, and unto the ages of
            ages. Amen
		</content>
    </prayer>
    



	 </hour>  