<hour>
    <info><hourName> صلاة نصف الليل</hourName></info>
    <info><description>صلاة نصف الليل تتحدث عن المجئ الثاني لإلهنا ومخلصنا السيد المسيح، وتنقسم تلك
الصلاة لثلاث خدمات، مثل صلاة السيد المسيح في بُستان جسثيماني.</description></info>
  
    <prayer>
        <title>بدء الصلاة</title>
        <content>تسبحة الخدمة الأولى من نصف الليل المبارك، أقدمها للمسيح ملكي والهي، وأرجوه أن يغفر
لي خطاياي.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    

    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور الثالث</title>
        <content>يا رب لماذا كثر الذين يحزنونني، كثيرون قاموا علي. كثيرون يقولون لنفسي، ليس له خلاص
بإلهه. أنت يا رب أنت هو ناصري، مجدي ورافع رأسي. بصوتي إلى الرب صرخت. فاستجاب لي من جبل قدسه.

أنا اضطجعت ونمت، ثم استيقظت لأن الرب ناصري. فلا أخاف من ربوات الجموع المحيطين بي القائمين على. قم يا
رب خلصني يا إلهي، لأنك ضربت كل من يعاديني باطلا. أسنان الخطاة سحقتها. للرب الخلاص وعلى شعبه بركته.
هلليلويا.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    

    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور السادس</title>
        <content>يا رب لا تبكتني بغضبك، ولا تؤدبني بسخطك. ارحمني يا رب فإني ضعيف، اشفني يا رب فإن
عظامي قد اضطربت ونفسي قد انزعجت جدا. وأنت يا رب فإلي متى؟ عد ونج نفسي، وأحيني من أجل رحمتك. لأنه ليس
في الموت من يذكرك ولا في الجحيم من يعترف لك. تعبت في تنهدي. أعوم كل ليلة سريري، وبدموعي أبل فراشي.
تعكرت من الغضب عيناي. شاخت من سائر أعدائي .

ابعدوا عنى يا جميع فاعلي الإثم. لأن الرب قد سمع صوت بكائي. الرب سمع تضرعي، الرب لصلاتي قبل، فليَخزَ
وليضطرب جدا جميع أعدائي، وليرتدوا إلى ورائهم بالخزي سريعا جدا. هلليلويا.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    

    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور الثاني عشر</title>
        <content>إلى متى يا رب تنساني؟ إلى الانقضاء؟ حتى متى تصرف وجهك عنى؟ إلى متى أردد هذه
المشورات في نفسي، وهذه الأوجاع في قلبي النهار كله؟ إلى متى يرتفع عدوى علي؟ انظر واستجب لي يا ربي
وإلهي. أنر عيني لئلا أنام نوم الموت، لئلا يقول عدوي: إني قد قويت عليه. الذين يحزنونني يتهللون إن أنا
زللت. أما أنا فعلى رحمتك توكلت.  يبتهج قلبي بخلاصك. أسبح الرب المحسنَ إلي، وأرتل لاسم الرب العلي.
هلليلويا.
        </content>
    </prayer>



    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور التاسع والستون</title>
        <content>اللهم التفت إلى معونتي، يا رب أسرع وأعنى. ليَخزَ ويخجل طالبو نفسي، وليرتد إلى خلف
ويخجل الذين يبتغون لي الشر. وليرجع بالخزي سريعا القائلون لي: نِعِمَّا نِعِمَّا. وليبتهج ويفرح بك
جميع الذين يلتمسونك، وليقل في كل حين محبو خلاصك: فليتعظم الرب. وأما أنا فمسكين وفقير، اللهم أعنى.
أنت معيني ومخلصي يا رب فلا تبطئ.هلليلويا.
		</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور الخامس والثمانون</title>
        <content>أمل يا رب أذنك واستمعني، لأني مسكين وبائس أنا. احفظ نفسي لأني بار، يا إلهي خلص عبدك
المتكل عليك. ارحمني يا رب، لأني إليك أصرخ اليوم كله. فرح نفس عبدك، لأني إليك يا رب رفعت نفسي. لأنك
أنت يا رب صالح ووديع، ورحمتك كثيرة لكافة المستغيثين بك.

أنصت يا رب إلي صلاتي، وأصغ إلى صوت تضرعي. في يوم شدتي إليك صرختُ فأجبتني. فليس لك شبيه في الآلهة يا
رب، ولا من يصنع كأعمالك. كل الأمم الذين خلقتهم يأتون ويسجدون أمامك يا رب، ويمجدون اسمك. لأنك أنت
عظيم وصانع العجائب، أنت وحدك الإله العظيم.

اهدني يا رب إلى طريقك فأسلك في حقك، ليفرح قلبي عند خوفه من اسمك. أعترف لك أيها الرب إلهي من كل قلبي،
وأمجد اسمك إلى الأبد. لأن رحمتك عظيمة على، وقد نجيت نفسي من الجحيم السفلي.

اللهم إن مخالفي الناموس قد قاموا علىّ ومجمع الأعزاء طلبوا نفسي، ولم يسبقوا أن يجعلوك أمامهم. وأنت
أيها الرب الإله أنت رؤوف ورحيم. أنت طويل الروح، وكثير الرحمة وصادق. انظر إلي وارحمني. أعطِ عزة
لعبدك، وخلص ابن أمتك. اصنع معي آية صالحة، ليرى ذلك مبغضي فيخزوا. لأنك  أنت يا رب أعنتني وعزيتني.
هلليلويا.
		</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور التسعون</title>
        <content>الساكن في عون العَليّ، يستريح في ظل إله السماء. يقول للرب أنت هو ناصري وملجأي، إلهي
فأتكل عليه. لأنه ينجيك من فخ الصياد، ومن كلمة مقلقة. في وسط منكبيه يظللك، وتحت جناحيه تعتصم، عدله
يحيط بك كالسلاح. فلا تخشى من خوف الليل، ولا من سهم يطير في النهار. ولا من أمر يسلك في الظلمة، ولا من
سقطة وشيطان الظهيرة. يسقط عن يسارك ألوف، وعن يمينك ربوات، وأما أنت فلا يقتربون إليك. بل بعينيك
تتأمل، ومجازاة الخطاة تبصر.

لأنك أنت يا رب رجائي. جعلتَ العليَّ ملجأك. فلا تصيبك الشرور، ولا تدنو ضربة من مسكنك. لأنه يوصى
ملائكته بك، ليحفظوك في سائر طرقك. وعلى أيديهم يحملونك، لئلا تعثر بحجر رجلك. تطأ الأفعى وملكَ الحيات،
وتسحق الأسد والتنين. لأنه على أتكل فأنجيه، أرَفعه (أستره) لأنه عرف اسمي. يدعوني فأستجيب له. معه أنا
في الشدة، أنقذه وأمجده. ومن طول الأيام أشبعه، وأريه خلاصي. هلليلويا.
		</content>
    </prayer>
    

    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور المائة والسادس عشر</title>
        <content>سبحوا الربَّ يا جميع الأمم ولتباركه كافة الشعوب. لأن رحمته قد ثبتت علينا وحق الرب
يدوم إلى الأبد هلليلويا.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>المزمور المائة والسابع عشر</title>
        <content>اعترفوا للرب لأنه صالح وأن إلى الأبد رحمته. ليقل بيت إسرائيل إنه صالح وإن إلى الأبد
رحمته. ليقل بيت هارون إنه صالح وإن إلى الأبد رحمته. ليقل أتقياء الرب إنه صالح وإن إلى الأبد رحمته.

في ضيقتي صرختُ إلى الرب، فاستجاب لي وأخرجني إلى الرحب. الرب عوني فلا أخشى ماذا يصنع بي الإنسان. الرب
لي معين وأنا أرى بأعدائي. الاتكال على الرب خير من الاتكال على البشر، الرجاء بالرب خير من الرجاء
بالرؤساء. كل الأمم أحاطوا بي وباسم الرب انتقمتُ منهم. أحاطوا بي احتياطا واكتنفوني، وباسم الرب
قهرتهم. أحاطوا بي مثل النحل حول الشهد، والتهبوا كنار في شوك، وباسم الرب انتقمت منهم. دفعتُ لأسقطَ
والرب عضدني. قوتي وتسبحتي هو الرب وقد صار لي خلاصا. صوت التهليل والخلاص في مساكن الأبرار. يمين الرب
صنعت قوة، يمين الرب رفعتني، يمين الرب صنعت قوة. فلن أموتَ بعدُ، بل أحيا وأحدث بأعمال الرب. تأديبا
أدبني الرب وإلى الموت لم يُسْلِمْني.

افتحوا لي أبواب البر لكي أدخل فيها وأعترفَ للرب. هذا هو باب الرب والصديقون يدخلون فيه. أعترف لك يا
رب لأنك استجبت لي وكنت لي مخلصا. الحجر الذي رذله البناءون هذا صار رأسا للزاوية. من قبل الرب كان هذا
وهو عجيب في أعيننا.

هذا هو اليوم الذي صنعه الرب. فلنبتهج ونفرح فيه. يا رب خلصنا. يا رب سهل طريقنا. مبارك الآتي باسم
الرب. باركناكم من بيت الرب. الله الرب أضاء علينا. رتبوا عيدا في الواصلين إلى قرون المذبح. أنت هو
إلهي فأشكرك، إلهي أنت فأرفعك. أعترف لك يا رب، لأنك استجبت لي وصرت لي مخلصا. اشكروا الرب فإنه صالح
وأن إلى الأبد رحمته هلليلويا
		</content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>1 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content> طوباهم الذين بلا عيب في الطريق، السالكون في ناموس الرب. طوباهم الذين يفحصون عن
شهاداته، ومن قلوبهم يطلبونه، لأن صانعي الإثم لم يهووا أن يسلكوا في سبله. أنت أمرت أن تحفظ وصاياك
جدا، فيا ليت طرقي تستقيم إلى حفظ حقوقك. حينئذ لا أخزى إذا ما اطلعت على جميع وصاياك. أشكرك يا رب
باستقامة قلبي، إذ عرفت أحكام عدلك. حقوقك أحفظ، فلا ترفضني إلى الغاية. (ذكصاسي فيلا نيثروبي ... المجد
لك يا محب البشر)

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>2 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
 		   <content>بماذا يقوم الشاب طريقه؟ بحفظه أقوالك. من كل قلبي طلبتك، فلا تبعدني عن وصاياك
أخفيت أقوالك في قلبي لكي لا أخطئ إليك. مبارك أنت يا رب علمني حقوقك. بشفتي أظهرت كل أحكام فمك، وفرحت
بطريق شهاداتك كما بكل غنى. بوصاياك أتكلم وأتفهم في طرقك، بفرائضك ألهج، ولا أنسى كلامك. (ذكصاسي…)

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>3 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>كافئ عبدك فأحيا وأحفظ أقوالك. اكشف عن عيني فـأرى عجائب من ناموسك. غريب أنا في الأرض
فلا تخفِ عنى وصاياك. اشتاقت نفسي إلى اشتهاء أحكامك في كل حين. إنك انتهرت المتكبرين الملاعين الذين
حادوا عن وصاياك. انزع عنى العار والخزي فإني لشهاداتك ابتغيتُ. جلس الرؤساء وتقاولوا على، أما عبدك
فكان يهتمُ بحقوقك، لأن شهاداتك هي درسي وحقوقك هي مشورتي (ذكصاسي…).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>4 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>لصقت بالتراب نفسي فأحيني ككلمتك. أخبرت بطرقك فاستجب لي. علمني حقوقك، وطريق عدلك
فهمني، فألهج في عجائبك. ذبلت نفسي من الحزن، فثبتني في أقوالك. طريق الظلم أبعد عنى وبناموسك ارحمني.
إني اخترت طريق الحق وأحكامك لم أنس. لصقتُ بشهاداتك يا رب فلا تخزني. في طريق وصاياك سعيتُ عندما وسعتَ
قلبي (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
       <title>5 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
 		<content>ضع لي يا رب ناموسا في طريق حقوقك فأتبعَه كل حين. فهمني فأبحث عن ناموسك وأحفظه بكل
قلبي. اهدني في سبيل وصاياك فإني إياها هويت. أمل قلبي إلى شهاداتك لا إلى الظلم. اردد عيني لئلا تعاينا
الأباطيل، وفى سبلك أحيني. ثبت قولك لعبدك في خوفك، وانزع عنى العار الذي حَذِرْتُ منه، فإن أحكامك
حلوة. هاأنذا قد اشتهيتُ وصاياك، فأحيني ببرك (ذكصاسي...).


        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
	   	<title>6 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
 		<content> لتأت عليّ رحمتك يا رب وخلاصك كقولك. فأجيب معيري بكلمة. لأني اتكلت على أقوالك، لا
تنزع من فمي قول الحق، لأني توكلت على أحكامك، واحفظ شريعتك في كل حين، إلى الأبد والى مدى الدهر. كنتُ
أسلك في السعة لأني لوصاياك ابتغيتُ. وتكلمت بشهاداتك قدام الملوك ولم أخزَ. ولهجتُ بوصاياك التي
أحببتُها جدا، ورفعت يدي إلى وصاياك التي وددتُها جدا. وتأملتُ فرائضك. (ذكصاسي...).
        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>7 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>اذكر لعبدك كلامك الذي جعلتني عليه أتكل. هذا الذي عزاني في مذلتي. لأن قولك أحياني.
إن المتكبرين تجاوزوا الناموس إلى الغاية، أما أنا فعن ناموسك لم أمِل. تذكرتُ أحكامك يا رب منذ الدهر
فتعزيتُ. الكآبة ملكتني من أجل الخطاة الذين تركوا ناموسك. حقوقك كانت لي مزاميرَ في موضع غربتي. ذكرتُ
في الليل اسمك يا رب، وحفظت شريعتك. هذا صار لي لأني طلبت حقوقك. (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>8 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>نصيبي أنت يا رب فقلت أن أحفظ وصاياك. ترضيت وجهك بكل قلبي، فارحمني كقولك. لأني تفكرت
في طرقك ورددت قدمي إلى شهاداتك. تهيأت ولم أتوانَ لحفظ وصاياك. رباطات الخطاة التفت على، أما شريعتك
فلم أنسَها. في نصف الليل نهضت لأشكرك على أحكام عدلك. شريك أنا لكل الذين يخافونك، وللحافظين وصاياك.
من رحمتك يا رب امتلأت الأرضُ فعلمني عدلك (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>9 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>خيرا صنعتَ مع عبدك يا رب حسب قولك، صلاحا وأدبا ومعرفة، علمني فإني قد صدقت وصاياك.
قبل أن أتواضع أنا تكاسلتُ. فلهذا حفظتُ كلامك. صالح أنت يا رب فبصلاحك علمني حقوقك. كثر عليّ ظلم
المتكبرين، وأنا بكل قلبي أبحث عن وصاياك. تجبن مثل اللبن قلبهم، وأنا لهجت بناموسك. خير لي أنك أذللتني
حتى أتعلمَ حقوقك. ناموس فمك خير لي من ألوف ذهب وفضة (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>10 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content> يداك صنعتاني وجبلتاني. فهمني فأتعلم وصاياك. الذين يخافونك يبصرونني ويفرحون، لأني
بكلامك وثقت. قد علمتُ يا رب أن أحكامك عادلة وبحق أذللتني. فلتأتِ عليّ رحمتك لتعزيني، نظير قولك
لعبدك. لتأتني رأفتك فأحيا فإن ناموسك هو درسي. وليخز المتكبرون لأنهم خالفوا الشرع عليّ ظلما، وأنا كنت
مثابرا على وصاياك. وليرجع إليّ الذين يتقونك ويعرفون عجائبك، وليصر قلبي بلا عيب في عدلك لكي لا أخزي
(ذكصاسي...).
        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>11 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>تاقت نفسي إلى خلاصك وعلى كلامك توكلت. كلت عيناي من انتظار أقوالك قائلتين: متى
تعزيني ؟ صرتُ مثل زق في جليد ولحقوقك لم أنس. كم هي أيام عبدك ؟ متى تجري لي حكما على الذين يضطهدونني؟
تكلم معي مخالفو الناموس بكلام هذيان، لكن ليس كناموسك يا رب، لأن كل وصاياك هي حق. وبظلم قد طردوني
فأعني؟ كادوا يفنونني على الأرض، أما أنا فلم أترك وصاياك. حسب رحمتك أحيني فأحفظ شهادات فمك
(ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>12 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>يا رب كلمتك دائمة في السموات إلى الأبد، وإلى جيل فجيل حقك. أسست الأرض فهي ثابتة
بأمرك، والنهار أيضا ثابت. لأن كل الأشياء متعبدة لك. لو لم تكن شريعتك تلاوتي لهلكتُ حينئذ في مذلتي.
وإلى الدهر لا أنسى وصاياك لأنك بها أحييتني يا رب. لك أنا فخلصني يا رب، لأني لوصاياك طلبتُ. إياي
انتظر الخطاة ليهلكوني، ولشهاداتك فهمت. لكل تمام رأيت منتهى أما وصاياك فواسعة جدا (ذكصاسي...).
        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>13 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>محبوب هو اسمك يا رب، فهو طولَ النهار تلاوتي. علمتني وصاياك أفضل من أعدائي، لأنها
ثابتة لي إلى الأبد. أكثر من جميع الذين يعلمونني فهمتُ، لأن شهادتك هي درسي. أكثر من الشيوخ فهمتُ،
لأني طلبتُ وصاياك. من كل طريق خبيث منعتُ رجليّ لكي أحفظ كلامك. عن كلامك لم أحد، لأنك وضعتَ لي
ناموسا. إن كلماتك حلوة في حلقي، أفضل من العسل والشهد في فمي. من وصاياك تفطنتُ، فلهذا أبغضت كل طرق
الظلم. (لأنك وضعتَ لي ناموسا) (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>14 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>مصباح لرجلي كلامك ونور لسبلي. حلفت فأقمت على حفظ أحكام عدلك. تذللت جدا إلى الغاية
يا رب، أحيني كقولك. تعهدات فمي باركها يا رب، وأحكامك علمني. نفسي في يديك كل حين، وناموسك لم أنسَ،
أخفى الخطاة لي فخا، ولم أضل عن وصاياك. ورثت شهاداتك إلى الأبد، لأنها بهجة قلبي. عطفت قلبي لأصنع برك
إلى الأبد (من أجل المكافأة) (ذكصاسي...).
        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>15 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>لمتجاوزي الناموس أبغضتُ ولناموسك أحببت. لأنك أنت معيني وناصري. وعلى كلامك توكلت.
ابعدوا عني أيها الأشرار فأفحص عن وصايا إلهي. عضدني حسب قولك فأحيا ولا تخيب رجائي. أعني فأخلص، وأدرس
في وصاياك كل حين. رذلتَ سائر الذين حادوا عن وصاياك لأن فكرهم ظلم. عصاة حسبتَ سائر خطاة الأرض، فلهذا
أحببتُ شهاداتك في كل حين. سمر خوفك في لحمي لأني من أحكامك جزعتُ (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>16 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content> قد أجريتُ حكما وعدلا فلا تسلمني إلى الذين يظلمونني. كن لعبدك كفيلا في الخير، لئلا
يجوزَ عليّ المتكبرون. عيناي قد ذبلتا من انتظار خلاصك وقول عدلك. اصنع مع عبدك حسب رحمتك، وحقوقك
علمني. عبدك أنا، فهمني فأعرف شهاداتك. إنه وقتٌ يعمل فيه للرب، لأنهم قد نقضوا ناموسك. لأجل هذا أحببتُ
وصاياك أفضل من الذهب والجوهر، ولأجل هذا بازاء كل وصاياك تقومتُ، وكل طريق ظلم أبغضتُ (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>17 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content> عجيبة هي شهاداتك لذلك حفظتها نفسي. إعلان أقوالك ينير لي، ويفهم الأطفال والصغار.
فتحت فهمي واجتذبتُ لي روحا، لأني لوصاياك اشتقتُ. انظر إليّ وارحمني كرحمتك للذين يحبون اسمك. قوم
خطواتي كقولك فلا يتسلط على أيُّ إثم. أنقذني من ظلم الناس فأحفظ وصاياك. أضئ بوجهك على عبدك وعلمني
حقوقك. غاصت عيناي في مجاري المياه، لأنهم لم يحفظوا ناموسك. (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>18 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>عادل أنت يا رب وقضاؤك مستقيم. أوصيتَ كثيرا بالعدل والحق اللذين هما شهاداتك. غيرة
بيتك أكلتني، لأن أعدائي نسوا وصاياك. ممحص قولك جدا، وعبدك أحبه. صغيرٌ أنا ومرذول وحقوقك لم أنسَ.
عدلك حق هو إلى الأبد، وكلامك حق هو. ضيق وشدة أدركاني، ووصاياك هي درسي. عادلة هي شهاداتك إلى الأبد.
فهمني فأحيا (ذكصاسي...).
        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>19 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>صرخت من كل قلبي، فاستجب لي يا رب. إني أبتغي حقوقك. صرختُ إليك فخلصني، لأحفظ
شهاداتك. سبقتُ وقمتُ قبل الوقتِ وصرخت، وعلى كلامك توكلتُ. سبقتْ عيناي وقت السحَر، لأتلو في جميع
أقوالك، فاسمع صوتي يا رب كرحمتك، وبحسب أحكامك أحيني. اقترب بالإثم الذين يطردونني، وعن ناموسك
ابتعدوا. قريب أنت يا رب، وكل وصاياك حق هي. منذ البدء عرفتُ من شهاداتك أنك إلى الدهر أسستها
(ذكصاسي...).
        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>20 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content>انظر إلى مذلتي وأنقذني، فإني لم أنس ناموسك. احكم لي في دعواي ونجني. من أجل كلامك
أحيني. بعيد هو الخلاص عن الخطاة، لأنهم لم يطلبوا حقوقك. رأفتك كثيرة جدا يا رب. حسب أحكامك أحيني.
كثيرون هُمُ الذين يضطهدونني ويحزنونني، وعن شهاداتك لم أجنح. رأيت الذين لا يفهمون فاكتأبت، لأنهم
لأقوالك لم يحفظوا. انظر يا رب، فإني أحببت وصاياك. برحمتك يا رب أحيني. بدء كلامك حقٌ، وإلي الأبد كل
أحكام عدلك (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>21 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content> الرؤساء اضطهدوني بلا سبب. من أقوالك جزع قلبي. أبتهج أنا بكلامك كمن وجد غنائمَ
كثيرة. أبغضتُ الظلم ورذلته، أما ناموسك فأحببته. سبع مرات في النهار سبحتك على أحكام عدلك. فليكن سلام
عظيم للذين يحبون اسمك، وليس لهم شك. توقعتُ خلاصك يا رب ووصاياك أحببتها. حفظتْ نفسي شهاداتك وأحببتها
جدا. حفظتُ وصاياك وشهاداتك، وكل طرقي أمامك يا رب. (ذكصاسي...).

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>22 المزمور المائة والثامن عشر</title>
        <content> فلتدن وسيلتي قدامك يا رب، كقولك فهمني. فلتدخل طلبتي إلى حضرتك يا رب، ككلمتك أحيني.
تفيض شفتاي السبح إذا ما علمتني حقوقك. لساني ينطق بأقوالك لأن جميع وصاياك عادلة. لتكن يدك لخلاصي
لأنني اشتهيت وصاياك. اشتقتُ إلى خلاصك يا رب، وناموسك هو تلاوتي. تحيا نفسي وتسبحك، وأحكامك تعينيني.
ضللت مثل الخروف الضال، فاطلب عبدك، فإني لوصاياك لم أنسَ هللويا.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    

	<prayer>
        <title>(إنجيل متى25: 1-13)</title>
        <content>حينئذٍ، يشبه ملكوت السموات عشر عذارى أخذن مصابيحهن وخرجن لاستقبال العريس. خمس منهن
كن جاهلات وخمس حكيمات. فأخذت الجاهلات مصابيحَهن ولم يأخذن معهن زيتا. وأما الحكيمات فأخذن زيتا في
آنيتهن مع مصابيحهن. ولما أبطأ العريس نعسن كلهن ونمن. ولما انتصف الليل صار صراخ: هوذا العريس قد أقبل
فقمن وأخرجن للقائه. حينئذ قامت أولئك العذارى جميعا وزينَّ مصابيحهن. فقالت الجاهلات للحكيمات أعطيننا
من زيتكن فإن مصابيحنا تنطفئ. فأجابت الحكيمات قائلات: لعله لا يكفينا وإياكن، فاذهبن بالحري إلى الباعة
وابتعن لكن. فلما ذهبن ليبتعن جاء العريس والمستعدات دخلن معه إلى العرس وأغلِق الباب. وأخيرا جاءت بقية
العذارى أيضا قائلات: ربنا ربنا افتح لنا. أما هو فأجاب وقال: الحق أقول لكن إني لا أعرفكن. فاسهروا إذن
لأنكم لا تعرفون اليوم ولا الساعة التي يأتي فيها ابن الإنسان (والمجد لله دائما)

        </content>
    </prayer>

	<prayer>
        <title>القطع</title>
        <content>¨   ها هو ذا العريس يأتي في نصف الليل، طوبى للعبد الذي يجده مستيقظا. أما الذي يجده متغافلا، فإنه غير مستحق المضي معه. فانظري يا نفسي لئلا تثقلي نوما، فتلقي خارج الملكوت. بل اسهري واصرخي قائلة: قدوس قدوس قدوس أنت يا الله، من أجل والدة الإله ارحمنا (ذوكصابترى).

¨   تفهمي يا نفسي ذلك اليومَ الرهيب واستيقظي، وأضيئي مصباحك بزيت البهجة. لأنك لا تعلمين متى يأتي نحوك الصوت القائل: ها هو ذا العريس قد أقبل. فانظري يا نفسي لا تنعسي، لئلا تقفي خارجا قارعة مثل الخمس العذارى الجاهلات، بل اسهري متضرعة لكي تلتقي المسيح الرب بدهن دسم، وينعم عليك بعرس مجده الإلهي الحقيقي (كي نين).

¨   أنت هي سور خلاصنا يا والدة الإله العذراء الحصن المنيع غير المنثلم أبطلي مشورة المعاندين، وحزن عبيدك رديه إلى فرح وحصني مدينتنا (ديرنا) وعن ملوكنا (رؤسائنا) حاربي، وتشفعي عن سلام العالم، لأنك أنت هي رجاؤنا يا والدة الإله (كي نين).

¨   أيها الملك السمائي المعزى، روح الحق، الحاضر في كل مكان والمالئ الكل، كنز الصالحات، ومعطى الحياة، هلم تفضل وحل فينا، وطهرنا من كل دنس أيها الصالح، وخلص نفوسنا. (ذوكصابترى … ).

¨   كما كنت مع تلاميذك أيها المخلص  وأعطيتهم السلام، هلم أيضا كن معنا وامنحنا سلامك وخلصنا ونج نفوسنا. (كى نين.. )

¨        إذا ما وقفنا في هيكلك المقدس نحسب كالقيام في السماء. يا والدة الإله، أنت هي باب السماء، افتحي لنا باب الرحمة.

كيري ليسون41 مرة
        </content>
    </prayer>

 	<prayer> 
		<title>قدوس قدوس قدوس</title>
		<content>قدوس، قدوس، قدوس، رب الصباؤوت.
السماء والأرض مملوءتان من مجدك وكرامتك. ارحمنا يا الله الآب ضابط الكل. أيها
الثالوث القدوس ارحمنا. أيها الرب إله القوات كن معنا، لأنه ليس لنا معين في
شدائدنا وضيقاتنا سواك.

حل واغفر واصفح لنا يا الله عن سيئاتنا، التي صنعناها بإرادتنا والتي صنعناها بغير
إرادتنا، التي فعلناها بمعرفة والتي فعلناها بغير معرفة، الخفية والظاهرة. يا رب
اغفرها لنا، من أجل اسمك القدوس الذي دعي علينا. كرحمتك يا رب وليس كخطايانا.

واجعلنا مستحقين أن نقول بشكر: أبانا الذي في السموات..
		</content>
	</prayer>


    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 120</title>
        <content>In my distress I cried to the LORD, And He heard me. Deliver my soul, O LORD, from
lying lips And from a deceitful tongue. What shall be given to you, Or what shall be done to you,
You false tongue? Sharp arrows of the warrior, With coals of the broom tree! Woe is me, that I
sojourn in Meshech, That I dwell among the tents of Kedar! My soul has dwelt too long With one who
hates peace. I am for peace; But when I speak, they are for war. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 121</title>
        <content>I will lift up my eyes to the hills—From whence comes my help? My help comes from
the LORD, Who made heaven and earth. He will not allow your foot to be moved; He who keeps you will
not slumber. Behold, He who keeps Israel Shall neither slumber nor sleep. The LORD is your keeper;
The LORD is your shade at your right hand. The sun shall not strike you by day, Nor the moon by
night. The LORD shall preserve you from all evil; He shall preserve your soul. The LORD shall
preserve your going out and your coming in From this time forth, and even forevermore. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
     <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 122</title>
        <content>I was glad when they said to me, “Let us go into the house of the LORD.” Our feet
have been standing Within your gates, O Jerusalem! Jerusalem is built As a city that is compact
together, Where the tribes go up, The tribes of the LORD, To the Testimony of Israel, To give thanks
to the name of the LORD. For thrones are set there for judgment, The thrones of the house of David.
Pray for the peace of Jerusalem: “May they prosper who love you. Peace be within your walls,
Prosperity within your palaces.” For the sake of my brethren and companions, I will now say, “Peace
be within you.” Because of the house of the LORD our God I will seek your good. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 123</title>
        <content>Unto You I lift up my eyes, O You who dwell in the heavens. Behold, as the eyes of
servants look to the hand of their masters, As the eyes of a maid to the hand of her mistress, So
our eyes look to the LORD our God, Until He has mercy on us. Have mercy on us, O LORD, have mercy on
us! For we are exceedingly filled with contempt. Our soul is exceedingly filled with the scorn of
those who are at ease. With the contempt of the proud. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    

    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 124</title>
        <content>“If it had not been the LORD who was on our side,” Let Israel now say— “If it had
not been the LORD who was on our side, When men rose up against us, Then they would have swallowed
us alive, When their wrath was kindled against us; Then the waters would have overwhelmed us, The
stream would have gone over our soul; Then the swollen waters Would have gone over our soul.”
Blessed be the LORD, Who has not given us as prey to their teeth. Our soul has escaped as a bird
from the snare of the fowlers; The snare is broken, and we have escaped. Our help is in thename of
the LORD, Who made heaven and earth. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 125</title>
        <content>Those who trust in the LORD Are like Mount Zion, Which cannot be moved, but abides
forever. As the mountains surround Jerusalem, So the LORD surrounds His people From this time forth
and forever. For the sceptre of wickedness shall not rest On the land allotted to the righteous,
Lest the righteous reach out their hands to iniquity. Do good, O LORD, to those who are good, And to
those who are upright in their hearts. As for such as turn aside to their crooked ways, The LORD
shall lead them away With the workers of iniquity. Peace be upon Israel. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 126</title>
        <content>When the LORD brought back the captivity of Zion, We were like those who dream.
Then our mouth was filled with laughter, And our tongue with singing. Then they said among the
nations, “The LORD has done great
things for them.” The LORD has done great things for us, Whereof we are
glad. Bring back our captivity, O LORD, As the streams in the South.
Those who sow in tears Shall reap in joy. He who continually goes forth
weeping, Bearing seed for sowing, Shall doubtless come again with
rejoicing, Bringing his sheaves with him. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 127</title>
        <content>Unless the LORD builds the house, They labour in vain who build it; Unless the LORD
guards the city, The watchman stays awake in vain. It is vain for you to rise up early, To sit up
late, To eat the bread of sorrows; For so He gives His beloved sleep. Behold, children are a
heritage from the LORD, The fruit of the womb is His reward. Like arrows in the hand of a warrior,
So are the children of one’s youth. Happy is the man who has his quiver full of them; They shall not
be ashamed, But shall speak with their enemies in the gate. Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 128</title>
        <content>Blessed is every one who fears the LORD, Who walks in His ways. When you eat the
labour of your hands, You shall be happy, and it shall be well with you. Your wife shall be like a
fruitful vine In the very heart of your house, Your children like olive plants All around your
table. Behold, thus shall the man be blessed Who fears the LORD. The LORD bless you out of Zion, And
may you see the good of Jerusalem All the days of your life. Yes, may you see your children’s
children. Peace be upon Israel! Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
  
   <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 129</title>
        <content>“Many a time they have afflicted me from my youth,” Let Israel now say— “Many a
time they have afflicted me from my youth; Yet they have not prevailed against me. The plowers
plowed on my back; They made their furrows long.” The LORD is righteous; He has cut in pieces the
cords of the wicked. Let all those who hate Zion Be put to shame and turned back. Let them be as the
grass on the housetops, Which withers before it grows up, With which the reaper does not fill his
hand, Nor he who binds sheaves, his arms. Neither let those who pass by them say, “The blessing of
the LORD be upon you; We bless you in the name of the LORD!” Alleluia.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
     <prayer>
        <title>The Gospel (Luke 7:36-50)</title>
        <content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel according to St. Luke may his blessings be with us
all. Amen. Then one of the Pharisees asked Him to eat with him. And He went to the Pharisee’s house,
and sat down to eat. And behold, a woman in the city who was a sinner, when she knew that Jesus sat
at the table in the Pharisee’s house, brought an alabaster flask of fragrant oil, and stood at His
feet behind Him weeping; and she began to wash His feet with her tears, and wiped them with the hair
of her head; and she kissed His feet and anointed them with the fragrant oil. Now when the Pharisee
who had invited Him saw this, he spoke to himself, saying, “This man, if He were a prophet, would
know who and what manner of woman this is who is touching Him, for she is a sinner.” And Jesus
answered and said to him, “Simon, I have something to say to you.” And he said, “Teacher, say it.”
“There was a certain creditor who had two debtors. One owed five hundred denarii, and the other
fifty. “And when they had nothing with which to repay, he freely forgave them both. Tell Me,
therefore, which of them will love him more?” Simon answered and said, “I suppose the one whom he
forgave more.” And He said to him, “You	have rightly judged.” Then He turned to the woman and
said to Simon, “Do you see this woman? I entered your house; you gave Me no water for My feet, but
she has washed My feet with her tears and wiped them with the hair of her head. “You gave Me no
kiss, but this woman has not ceased to kiss My feet since the time I came in. “You did not anoint My
head with oil, but this woman has anointed My feet with fragrant oil. “Therefore I say to you, her
sins, which are	many, are forgiven, for she loved much. But to whom little is forgiven, the same
loves little.” And He said to her, “Your sins are forgiven.” And those who sat at the table with Him
began to say to themselves, “Who is this who even forgives sins?” Then He said to the woman, “Your
faith has saved you. Go in peace.’ Glory be to God forever. Amen.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
      <prayer>
            <title>The Parts</title>
            <content>Give me, Lord, fountains of many tears as You did in the past to the sinful
woman. Make me worthy to shed my tears on Your feet which took me to the right path and offer You
the best of perfumes. Grant me to live pure and repentant, so that I can hear a joyful voice: “Your
faith has saved you’. Thok-sa-patri Keey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty. When I am conscious of my sins,
and when I think of Your judgement, I fear and tremble and run to You, O’ God, do not turn away my
supplications. My undefiled Lord, have mercy upon me. Ke-neen Kea-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon.
Amen. Heavens bless You, O full of grace, the ever Virgin Bride. We glorify Your immaculate birth of
Jesus Christ which is beyond our comprehension. O’Mother of God, Mother of mercy and salvation,
plead for the redemption of our souls. Ke-neen Kea-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen. O’
Heavenly King, the Spirit of truth, the comforter,	who is every where and fills everybody.
You	are the treasure of goodness and giver of life, we ask You to graciously come and dwell with
in us, purify us from iniquity and save our souls. Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty.
Lord, abide with us as You did with the apostles, when You gave them Your peace, we ask You to grant
us Your peace, our Saviour; save us and spare our souls. Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton
E-onon. Amen. Whenever we stand in Your Holy Temple, we are considered as those who abide in heaven.
O’ Mother of God, you are the gate of heaven, open to us the door of mercy. Lord have mercy (Kir-ye
ley-son) 41 times.
            </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer> 
		<title>قدوس قدوس قدوس</title>
		<content>قدوس، قدوس، قدوس، رب الصباؤوت.
السماء والأرض مملوءتان من مجدك وكرامتك. ارحمنا يا الله الآب ضابط الكل. أيها
الثالوث القدوس ارحمنا. أيها الرب إله القوات كن معنا، لأنه ليس لنا معين في
شدائدنا وضيقاتنا سواك.

حل واغفر واصفح لنا يا الله عن سيئاتنا، التي صنعناها بإرادتنا والتي صنعناها بغير
إرادتنا، التي فعلناها بمعرفة والتي فعلناها بغير معرفة، الخفية والظاهرة. يا رب
اغفرها لنا، من أجل اسمك القدوس الذي دعي علينا. كرحمتك يا رب وليس كخطايانا.

واجعلنا مستحقين أن نقول بشكر: أبانا الذي في السموات..
		</content>
	</prayer>

    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 130</title>
		<content>Out of the depths I have cried to You, O LORD; LORD, hear my voice! Let Your ears
be attentive To the voice of my supplications. If You, LORD, should mark iniquities, O Lord, who
could stand? But there is forgiveness with You, That You may be feared. I wait for the LORD, my soul
waits, And in His word I do hope. My soul waits for the Lord More than those who watch for the
morning—I say, more than those who watch for the morning. O Israel, hope in the LORD; For with the
LORD there is mercy, And with Him is abundant redemption. And He shall redeem Israel From all his
iniquities. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 131</title>
        <content>LORD, my heart is not haughty, Nor my eyes lofty. Neither do I concern myself with
great matters, Nor with things too profound for me. Surely I have calmed and quieted my soul, Like a
weaned child with his mother; Like a weaned child is my soul within me. O Israel, hope in the LORD
From this time forth and forever. Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 132</title>
        <content>LORD, remember David And all his afflictions; How he swore to the LORD, And vowed
to the Mighty God of Jacob: “Surely I will not go into the chamber of my house, Or go up to the
comfort of my bed; I will not give sleep to my eyes Or slumber to my eyelids, Until I find a place
for the LORD, A dwelling place for the Mighty God of Jacob.” Behold, we heard of it in Ephrathah; We
found it in the fields of the woods. Let us go into His tabernacle; Let us worship at His footstool.
Arise, O LORD, to Your resting place, You and the ark of Your strength. Let Your priests be clothed
with righteousness, And let Your saints shout for joy. For Your servant David’s sake, Do not turn
away the face of Your Anointed. The LORD has sworn in truth to David; He will not turn from it: “I
will set upon your throne the fruit of your body. If your sons will keep My covenant And My
testimony which I shall teach them, Their sons also shall sit upon your throne forevermore.” For the
LORD has chosen Zion; He has desired it for His habitation: “This is My resting place forever; Here
I will dwell, for I have desired it. I will abundantly bless her provision; I will satisfy her poor
with bread. I will also clothe her priests with salvation, And her saints shall shout aloud for joy.
There I will make the horn of David grow; I will prepare a lamp for My Anointed. His enemies I will
clothe with shame, But upon Himself His crown shall flourish.” Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 133</title>
        <content>Behold, how good and how pleasant it is For brethren to dwell together in unity! It
is like the precious oil upon the head, Running down on the beard, The beard of Aaron, Running down
on the edge of his garments. It is like the dew of Hermon, Descending upon the mountains of Zion;
For there the LORD commanded the blessing—Life for evermore. Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 134</title>
        <content>Behold, bless the LORD, All you servants of the LORD, Who by night stand in the
house of the LORD! Lift up your hands in the sanctuary, And bless the LORD. The LORD who made heaven
and earth Bless you from Zion! Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 137</title>
        <content>By the rivers of Babylon, There we sat down, yea, we wept When we remembered Zion.
We hung our harps Upon the willows in the midst of it. For there those who carried us away captive
required of us a song, And those who plundered us required of us mirth, Saying, “Sing us one of the
songs of Zion!” How shall we sing the Lord’s song In a foreign land? If I forget you, O Jerusalem,
Let my right hand forget her skill! If I do not remember you, Let my tongue cling to the roof of my
mouth—If I do not exalt Jerusalem Above my chief joy. Remember, O LORD, against the sons of Edom The
day of Jerusalem, Who said, “Raze it, raze it, To its very foundation!” O daughter of Babylon, who
are to be destroyed, Happy shall he be who repays you as you have served us! Happy shall he be who
takes and dashes Your little ones against the rock. Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 138</title>
        <content>I will praise You with my whole heart; Before the gods I will sing praises to You.
I will worship toward Your holy temple, And praise Your name For Your loving-kindness and Your
truth; For You have magnified Your word above all Your name. In the day when I cried out, You
answered me, And made me bold with strength in my soul. All the kings of the earth shall praise You,
O LORD, When they hear the words of Your mouth. Yes, they shall sing of the ways of the LORD, For
great is the glory of the LORD. Though the LORD is on high, Yet He regards the lowly; But the proud
He knows from afar. Though I walk in the midst of trouble, You will revive me; You will stretch out
Your hand Against the wrath of my enemies, And Your right hand will save me. The LORD will perfect
that which concerns me; Your mercy, O LORD, endures forever; Do not forsake the works of Your hands.
Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 141</title>
        <content>LORD, I cry out to You; Make haste to me! Give ear to my voice when I cry out to
You. Let my prayer be set before You as incense, The lifting up of my hands as the evening
sacrifice. Set a guard, O LORD, over my mouth; Keep watch over the door of my lips. Do not incline
my heart to any evil thing, To practice wicked works With men who work iniquity; And do not let me
eat of their delicacies. Let the righteous strike me; It shall be a kindness. And let him reprove
me; It shall be as excellent oil; Let my head not refuse it. For still my prayer is against the
deeds of the wicked. Their judges are overthrown by the sides of the cliff, And they hear my words,
for they are sweet. Our bones are scattered at the mouth of the grave, As when one ploughs and
breaks up the earth. But my eyes are upon You, O God the Lord; In You I take refuge; Do not leave my
soul destitute. Keep me from the snares which they have laid for me, And from the traps of the
workers of iniquity. Let the wicked fall into their own nets, While I escape safely. Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 142</title>
        <content>I cry out to the LORD with my voice; With my voice to the LORD I make my
supplication. I pour out my complaint before Him; I declare before Him my trouble. When my spirit
was overwhelmed within me, Then You knew my path. In the way in which I walk They have secretly set
a snare for me. Look on my right hand and see, For there is no one who acknowledges me; Refuge has
failed me; No one cares for my soul. I cried out to You, O LORD: I said, “You are my refuge, My
portion in the land of the living. Attend to my cry, For I am brought very low; Deliver me from my
persecutors, For they are stronger than I. Bring my soul out of prison, That I may praise Your name;
The righteous shall surround me, For You shall deal bountifully with me.” Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 146</title>
        <content>Praise the LORD! Praise the LORD, O my soul! While I live I will praise the LORD; I
will sing praises to my God while I have my being. Do not put your trust in princes, Nor in a son of
man, in whom there is no help. His spirit departs, he returns to his earth; In that very day his
plans perish. Happy is he who has the God of Jacob for his help, Whose hope is in the LORD his God,
Who made heaven and earth, The sea, and all that is in them; Who keeps truth forever, Who executes
justice for the oppressed, Who gives food to the hungry. The LORD gives freedom to the prisoners.
The LORD opens the eyes of the blind; The LORD raises those who are bowed down; The LORD loves the
righteous. The LORD watches over the strangers; He relieves the fatherless and widow; But the way of
the wicked He turns upside down. The LORD shall reign forever—Your God, O Zion, to all generations.
Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 147:1-11</title>
        <content>Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; For it is pleasant, and
praise is beautiful. The LORD builds up Jerusalem; He gathers together the outcasts of Israel. He
heals the broken-hearted And binds up their wounds. He counts the number of the stars; He calls them
all by name. Great is our Lord, and mighty in power; His understanding is infinite. The LORD lifts
up the humble; He casts the wicked down to the ground. Sing to the LORD with thanksgiving; Sing
praises on the harp to our God, Who covers the heavens with clouds, Who prepares rain for the earth,
Who makes grass to grow on the mountains. He gives to the beast its food, And to the young ravens
that cry. He does not delight in the strength of the horse; He takes no pleasure in the legs of a
man. The LORD takes pleasure in those who fear Him, In those who hope in His mercy. Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 147:12-20</title>
        <content>Praise the LORD, O Jerusalem! Praise your God, O Zion! For He has strengthened the
bars of your gates; He has blessed your children within you. He makes peace in your borders, And
fills you with the finest wheat. He sends out His command to the earth; His word runs very swiftly.
He gives snow like wool; He scatters the frost like ashes; He casts out His hail like morsels; Who
can stand before His cold? He sends out His word and melts them; He causes His wind to blow, and the
waters flow. He declares His word to Jacob, His statutes and His judgments to Israel. He has not
dealt thus with any nation; And as for His judgments, they have not known them. Alleluia.
         </content>
    </prayer>
		
	<prayer>
        <title>The Gospel (Luke 12:32-46)</title>
        <content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel
according to St. Luke
may his blessings be with us all. Amen.
“Do not fear, little flock, for it is your Father’s
good pleasure to give you the kingdom.” Sell what
you have and give alms; provide yourselves money
bags which do not grow old, a treasure in the heavens
that does not fail, where no thief approaches nor
moth destroys. “For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also. “Let your waist be girded
and
your lamps burning; “and you yourselves be like
men who wait for their master, when he will return
from the wedding, that when he comes and knocks
they may open to him immediately. “Blessed are
those servants whom the master, when he comes,
will find watching. Assuredly, I say to you that he
will gird himself and have them sit down to eat, and
will come and serve them. “And if he should come in
the second watch, or come in the third watch, and
find them so, blessed are those servants. “But know
this, that if the master of the house had known what
hour the thief would come, he would have watched
and not allowed his house to be broken into. “Therefore
you also be ready, for the Son of Man is coming
at an hour you do not expect.” Then Peter said to
Him, “Lord, do You speak this parable only to us, or
to all people?” And the Lord said, “Who then is that
faithful and wise steward, whom his master will
make ruler over his household, to give them their
portion of food in due season? “Blessed is that servant
whom his master will find so doing when he
comes. “Truly, I say to you that he will make him
ruler over all that he has. “But if that servant says in
his heart, ‘My master is delaying his coming,’ and
begins to beat the menservants and maidservants,
and to eat and drink and be drunk, “the master of that
servant will come on a day when he is not looking for him, and at an hour when he is not aware; and
will cut
him in two and appoint him his portion with the
unbelievers.
Glory be to God forever. Amen.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Parts</title>
        <content>
O’ Lord look at my weakness with a compassionate
eye, for my life is nearing its end and with deeds
like mine, I shall have no salvation. I pray to You, my
Lord, to look with merciful eyes, at me weakness and
my disgrace and my humility, and save me. Thok-sapatri
Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty.
Wake up, my soul and be careful, your judge is
present. Consider the awesome time of judgement,
there will be no mercy on those who did not have
mercy on others. O’ Saviour, help me, for You alone
have such love for humanity. Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Keis-
touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
O’ Graceful Mother of God, help those who come
to your faith. As we glorify Your immaculate birth of
Our Saviour. Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas
ton E-onon. Amen.
O’ Heavenly King, the Spirit of truth, the comforter,
who is every where and fills everybody. You
are the treasure of goodness and giver of life, we ask
You to graciously come and dwell with in us, purify us from iniquity and save our souls.
Thok-sa-patri
Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty.
Lord, abide with us as You did with the apostles,
when You gave them Your peace, we ask You to
grant us Your peace, our Saviour; save us and spare
our souls. Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton
E-onon. Amen.
Whenever we stand in Your Holy Temple, we are
considered as those who abide in heaven. O’ Mother
of God, you are the gate of heaven, open to us the
door of mercy.
Lord have mercy (Kir-ye ley-son) 41 times.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer> 
		<title>قدوس قدوس قدوس</title>
		<content>قدوس، قدوس، قدوس، رب الصباؤوت.
السماء والأرض مملوءتان من مجدك وكرامتك. ارحمنا يا الله الآب ضابط الكل. أيها
الثالوث القدوس ارحمنا. أيها الرب إله القوات كن معنا، لأنه ليس لنا معين في
شدائدنا وضيقاتنا سواك.

حل واغفر واصفح لنا يا الله عن سيئاتنا، التي صنعناها بإرادتنا والتي صنعناها بغير
إرادتنا، التي فعلناها بمعرفة والتي فعلناها بغير معرفة، الخفية والظاهرة. يا رب
اغفرها لنا، من أجل اسمك القدوس الذي دعي علينا. كرحمتك يا رب وليس كخطايانا.

واجعلنا مستحقين أن نقول بشكر: أبانا الذي في السموات..
		</content>
	</prayer>


    <prayer>
        <title>The Gospel (Luke 2:29-32)</title>
        <content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel
according to St. Luke
may his blessings be with us all Amen.
“Lord, now You are letting Your servant depart in
peace, according to Your word; for my eyes have
seen Your salvation which You have prepared before
the face of all peoples, a light to bring revelation to the
Gentiles, and the glory of Your people Israel.”
Glory be to God forever. Amen.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
     <prayer>
        <title>The Creed</title>
        <content>Truly we believe in One God, the Almighty God the Father, maker of heaven and
earth, of all things visible and invisible. We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ the only begotten
Son of God, born of the Father before all ages; light out of light, true God out of true God,
begotten not made; consubstantial with the Father, through whom all things came into being. He
descended from heaven for us and for our salvation, and was incarnated from the Holy Spirit and of
the Virgin Mary, and became man. He was crucified for us at the time of Pontius Pilate. He suffered
and was buried; arose from the dead on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures; He ascended
to the heavens and sat at the right hand of the Father; He shall also come in His glory to judge the
living and the dead; of whose kingdom there will be no end. Truly we believe in the Holy Spirit, the
Lifegiving Lord, who proceeds from the Father, we worship and glorify Him together with the Father
and the Son, who spoke in the prophets. And in one, holy, universal and Apostolic Church. We
acknowledge one baptism for the remission of sins. And we look for the resurrection of the dead and
the life of the world to come. Amen. Lord have mercy (Kir-ye ley-son) 41 times.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
     <prayer> 
		<title>قدوس قدوس قدوس</title>
		<content>قدوس، قدوس، قدوس، رب الصباؤوت.
السماء والأرض مملوءتان من مجدك وكرامتك. ارحمنا يا الله الآب ضابط الكل. أيها
الثالوث القدوس ارحمنا. أيها الرب إله القوات كن معنا، لأنه ليس لنا معين في
شدائدنا وضيقاتنا سواك.

حل واغفر واصفح لنا يا الله عن سيئاتنا، التي صنعناها بإرادتنا والتي صنعناها بغير
إرادتنا، التي فعلناها بمعرفة والتي فعلناها بغير معرفة، الخفية والظاهرة. يا رب
اغفرها لنا، من أجل اسمك القدوس الذي دعي علينا. كرحمتك يا رب وليس كخطايانا.

واجعلنا مستحقين أن نقول بشكر: أبانا الذي في السموات..
		</content>
	</prayer>
	
    <prayer>
        <title>The Absolution</title>
        <content>Lord Jesus Christ, Son of our eternal God, enlighten
our minds to understand Your life giving
words. Raise us from the darkness of mortal sin,
make us worthy to be steady in virtue. When You
come to judge the world, grant us to hear the joyful
call; “Come you that are blessed by My Father! Come
and inherit the Kingdom that has been prepared for
you since the creation of the world!”
Lord grant us to attend at that hour without fear,
anxiety or condemnation. Do not judge us according
to our sins, because You alone, have such compassion,
patience and mercy. May You accept these
prayers through the pleadings of the Holy Mother of
God, Virgin Mary and all the saints. Amen.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer> 
		<title>طلبة تصلى آخر كل ساعة</title>
		<content>ارحمنا يا الله ثم ارحمنا.
يا من في كل وقت وكل ساعة، في السماء وعلى الأرض، مسجود له وممجد. المسيح إلهنا
الصالح، الطويل الروح، الكثير الرحمة، الجزيل التحنن، الذي يحب الصديقين ويرحم
الخطاة الذين أولهم أنا. الذي لا يشاء موت الخاطئ مثل ما يرجع ويحيا. الداعي الكل
إلى الخلاص لأجل الموعد بالخيرات المنتظرة.

يا رب اقبل منا في هذه الساعة وكل ساعة طلباتنا. سهل حياتنا، وأرشدنا إلى العمل
بوصاياك. قدس أرواحنا. طهر أجسامنا. قوم أفكارنا. نق نياتنا. اشف أمراضنا واغفر
خطايانا. ونجنا من كل حزن رديء ووجع قلب. أحطنا بملائكتك القديسين، لكي نكون
بمعسكرهم محفوظين ومرشدين، لنصل إلى اتحاد الإيمان وإلى معرفة مجدك غير المحسوس
وغير المحدود، فإنك مبارك إلى الأبد. أمين.

اللهم اجعلنا مستحقين أن نقول بشكر: أبانا الذي في السموات...
		</content>
	</prayer>
    


</hour>

