<hour>
    <info>
        <hourName>The First Hour</hourName>
        <description>Instituted to commemorate the hour at which our Lord Jesus Christ rose from the dead. To be read in the morning, to give thanks to God for the beginning of a new day, and to glorify Him for His resurrection.</description>
    </info>
    <prayer>
        <title>Introductory Prayer</title>
        <content>† In the name of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, one God. Amen.
            
† Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
            
† Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit, now and forever and ever. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Lord's Prayer</title>
        <content>O’ Lord make us worthy to pray thankfully:
            
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy Name. Thy Kingdom come. Thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us; and lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through Jesus Christ, our Lord, for Thine is the Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory forever. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Thanksgiving Prayer</title>
        <content>Let us give thanks to the gracious and merciful God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, for He has protected, assisted, preserved and accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.

Let us also ask Him the Almighty God, to keep us in peace this blessed day, and all the days of our life. O Lord, Master and Almighty God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, we thank You on every occasion, in every condition and for all things, for You have protected, assisted, preserved, accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.

Therefore, we ask and appeal to Your goodness, O Lover-of-mankind that You grant us to conclude this blessed day and all the days of our life in peace and in Your fear. All envy, all temptation, all works of Satan, all intrigues of the wicked; rising up of enemies, seen and unseen; do cast away from us and all your people, and from this Holy place.

Grant us the endowments and benefactions, as You have given us the authority to trample on serpents and scorpions, and over all the power of the enemy. Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through the grace, mercy and love of mankind of Your only begotten Son, our Lord God and Saviour, Jesus Christ. Glory, honour, dominion and worship are due to You together with Him and the Life-Giving and consubstantial Holy Spirit, now and forever. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Psalm 51</title>
        <content>Have mercy upon me, O God, According to Your loving-kindness; According to the multitude of Your tender mercies, Blot out my transgressions. Wash from my sin. For I acknowledge my transgressions, And my sin is ever before me. Against You, You only, have I sinned, And done this evil in Your sight—That You may be found just when You speak,And blameless when You judge.

Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity, And in sin my mother conceived me. Behold, You desire truth in the inward parts, And in the hidden part You will make me to know wisdom. Purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean; Wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow. Make me to hear joy and gladness, That the bones which You have broken may rejoice. Hide Your face from my sins, And blot out all my iniquities.
            
Create in me a clean heart, O God, And renew a steadfast spirit within me. Do not cast me away from Your presence, And do not take Your Holy Spirit from me. Restore to me the joy of Your salvation, And uphold me with Your generous Spirit. Then I will teach transgressors Your ways, And sinners shall be converted to You. Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, The God of my salvation, And my tongue shall sing aloud of Your righteousness.  O Lord, open my lips, And my mouth shall show forth Your praise. For You do not desire sacrifice, or else I would give it; You do not delight in burnt offering.

The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit, A broken and a contrite heart—These, O God, You will not despise. Do good in Your good pleasure to Zion; Build the walls of Jerusalem. Then You shall be pleased with the sacrifices of righteousness, With burnt offering and whole burnt offering; Then they shall offer bulls on Your altar. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
   	<prayer>
        <title>Come, Let Us Worship</title>
        <content>O’ Come, let us worship; O’ Come, let us ask Christ our God. O’ Come, let us worship; O’ Come, let us ask Christ our King. O’ Come, let us worship; O’ Come, let us implore Christ our Saviour. Our Lord Jesus Christ, the word of God, keep us through the intercessions of St Mary and all your Saints, and let us enjoy a fresh start.
            
Have mercy upon us according to Your will forever. The night had passed away, we thank You, O’ Lord, and ask You to keep us this day without sin and deliver us.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>The Pauline (Ephesians 4:1-5)</title>
		<content>From St. Paul’s Epistle to the Ephesians.

“I, therefore, the prisoner of the Lord, beseech you to lead a life worthy of the calling with which you were called, with all lowliness and gentleness, with long-suffering, bearing with one another in love, endeavouring to keep the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace. There is one body and one Spirit, just as you were called in one hope of your calling; one Lord, one faith, one baptism;”</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Our Orthodox Faith</title>
		<content>One is God; the Father of all.

One is his Son who became man, died and rose from the dead on the third day, and raised us up with Him.

One is the Holy Spirit, the Comforter, and the same in nature, who proceeds from the Father, and sanctifies the whole creation, teaching us to worship the Holy Trinity in one divinity, one nature. We praise Him, and we bless Him forever. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<content>The Prayer of the First Hour of this blessed day is offered to Christ my King and my God, beseeching Him to forgive my sins.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 1</title>
		<content>Blessed is the man Who walks not in the counsel of the ungodly, Nor stands in the path of sinners, Nor sits in the seat of the scornful; But his delight is in the law of the LORD, And in His law he meditates day and night.
            
He shall be like a tree Planted by the rivers of water, That brings forth its fruit in its season, Whose leaf also shall not wither; And whatever he does shall prosper. The ungodly are not so, But are like the chaff which the wind drives away. Therefore the ungodly shall not stand in the judgment, Nor sinners in the congregation of the righteous. For the LORD knows the way of the righteous, But the way of the ungodly shall perish. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 2</title>
		<content>Why do the nations rage, And the people plot a vain thing? The kings of the earth set themselves, And the rulers take counsel together, Against the LORD and against His Anointed, saying, “Let us break Their bonds in pieces And cast away Their cords from us.” He who sits in the heavens shall laugh; The LORD shall hold them in derision.
            
Then He shall speak to them in His wrath, And distress them in His deep displeasure: “Yet I have set My King On My holy hill of Zion.” “I will declare the decree: The LORD has said to Me, ‘You are My Son, Today I have begotten You. Ask of Me, and I will give You The nations for Your inheritance, And the ends of the earth for Your possession. You shall break them with a rod of iron; You shall dash them in pieces like a potter’s vessel.’ ”
            
Now therefore, be wise, O kings; Be instructed, you judges of the earth. Serve the LORD with fear, And rejoice with trembling. Kiss the Son, lest He be angry, And you perish in the way, When His wrath is kindled but a little. Blessed are all those who put their trust in Him. Alleluia</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 3</title>
		<content>LORD, how they have increased who trouble me! Many are they who rise up against me. Many are they who say of me, “There is no help for him in God.” But You, O LORD, are a shield for me, My glory and the One who lifts up my head. I cried to the LORD with my voice, And He heard me from His holy hill.
            
I lay down and slept; I awoke, for the LORD sustained me. I will not be afraid of ten thousands of people Who have set themselves against me all around. Arise, O LORD; Save me, O my God! For You have struck all my enemies on the cheekbone; You have broken the teeth of the ungodly. Salvation belongs to the LORD. Your blessing is upon Your people. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 4</title>
		<content>Hear me when I call, O God of my righteousness! You have relieved me when I was in distress; Have mercy on me, and hear my prayer. How long, O you sons of men, Will you turn my glory to shame? How long will you love worthlessness And seek falsehood? But know that the LORD has set apart for Himself him who is godly; The LORD will hear when I call to Him. Be angry, and do not sin.
            
Meditate within your heart on your bed, and be still. Offer the sacrifices of righteousness, And put your trust in the LORD. There are many who say, “Who will show us any good?” LORD, lift up the light of Your counte nance upon us. You have put gladness in my heart, More than in the season that their grain and wine increased. I will both lie down in peace, and sleep; For You alone, O LORD, make me dwell in safety. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 5</title>
		<content>Give ear to my words, O LORD, Consider my meditation. Give heed to the voice of my cry, My King and my God, For to You I will pray. My voice You shall hear in the morning, O LORD; In the morning I will direct it to You, And I will look up. For You are not a God who takes pleasure in wickedness, Nor shall evil dwell with You. The boastful shall not stand in Your sight; You hate all workers of iniquity.
            
You shall destroy those who speak falsehood; The LORD abhors the bloodthirsty and deceitful man. But as for me, I will come into Your house in the multitude of Your mercy; In fear of You I will worship toward Your holy temple. Lead me, O LORD, in Your righteousness because of my enemies; Make Your way straight before my face.
            
For there is no faithfulness in their mouth; Their inward part is destruction; Their throat is an open tomb; They flatter with their tongue. Pronounce them guilty, O God! Let them fall by their own counsels; Cast them out in the multitude of their transgressions, For they have rebelled against You. But let all those rejoice who put their trust in You; Let them ever shout for joy, because You defend them; Let those also who love Your name Be joyful in You. For You, O LORD, will bless the righteous; With favour You will surround him as with a shield. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 6</title>
		<content>O LORD, do not rebuke me in Your anger, Nor chasten me in Your hot displeasure. Have mercy on me, O LORD, for I am weak; O LORD, heal me, for my bones are troubled.
            
My soul also is greatly troubled; But You, O LORD—how long? Return, O LORD, deliver me! Oh, save me for Your mercies’ sake! For in death there is no remembrance of You; In the grave who will give You thanks? I am weary with my groaning; All night I make my bed swim; I drench my couch with my tears.
            
My eye wastes away because of grief; It grows old because of all my enemies. Depart from me, all you workers of iniquity; For the LORD has heard the voice of my weeping. The LORD has heard my supplication; The LORD will receive my prayer. Let all my enemies be ashamed and greatly troubled; Let them turn back and be ashamed suddenly. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 8</title>
		<content>O LORD, our Lord, How excellent is Your name in all the earth, You who set Your glory above the heavens! Out of the mouth of babes and infants You have ordained strength, Because of Your enemies, That You may silence the enemy and the avenger.
            
When I consider Your heavens, the work of Your fingers, The moon and the stars, which You have ordained, What is man that You are mindful of him, And the son of man that You visit him? For You have made him a little lower than the angels, And You have crowned him with glory and honour. You have made him to have dominion over the works of Your hands; You have put all things under his feet, All sheep and oxen—Even the beasts of the field, The birds of the air, And the fish of the sea That pass through the paths of the seas. O LORD, our Lord, How excellent is Your name in all the earth! Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 12</title>
		<content>Help, LORD, for the godly man ceases! For the faithful disappear from among the sons of men. They speak idly everyone with his neighbour; With flattering lips and a double heart they speak.
            
May the LORD cut off all flattering lips, And the tongue that speaks proud things, Who have said, “With our tongue we will prevail; Our lips are our own; Who is lord over us?” “For the oppression of the poor, for the sighing of the needy, Now I will arise,” says the LORD; “I will set him in the safety for which he yearns.”
            
The words of the LORD are pure words,Like silver tried in a furnace of earth, Purified seven times. You shall keep them, O LORD, You shall preserve them from this generation forever. The wicked prowl on every side, When vileness is exalted among the sons of men. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 13</title>
		<content>How long, O LORD? Will You forget me forever? How long will You hide Your face from me? How long shall I take counsel in my soul, Having sorrow in my heart daily? How long will my enemy be exalted over me? Consider and hear me, O LORD my God; Enlighten my eyes, Lest I sleep the sleep of death; Lest my enemy say, “I have prevailed against him”; Lest those who trouble me rejoice when I am moved.
            
But I have trusted in Your mercy; My heart shall rejoice in Your salvation. I will sing to the LORD, Because He has dealt bountifully with me. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 15</title>
		<content>LORD, who may abide in Your tabernacle? Who may dwell in Your holy hill? He who walks uprightly, And works righteousness, And speaks the truth in his heart; He who does not backbite with his tongue, Nor does evil to his neighbour, Nor does he take up a reproach against his friend; In whose eyes a vile person is despised, But he honours those who fear the LORD; He who swears to his own hurt and does not change; He who does not put out his money at usury, Nor does he take a bribe against the innocent. He who does these things shall never be moved. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 16</title>
		<content>Preserve me, O God, for in You I put my trust. O my soul, you have said to the LORD, “You are my Lord, My goodness is nothing apart from You”— And to the saints who are on the earth, “They are the excellent ones, in whom is all my delight.”
            
Their sorrows shall be multiplied who hasten after another god; Their drink offerings of blood I will not offer, Nor take up their names on my lips. You, O LORD, are the portion of my inheritance and my cup; You maintain my lot. The lines have fallen to me in pleasant places; Yes, I have a good inheritance. I will bless the LORD who has given me counsel; My heart also instructs me in the night seasons.
            
I have set the LORD always before me; Because He is at my right hand I shall not be moved. Therefore my heart is glad, and my glory rejoices; My flesh also will rest in hope. For You will not leave my soul in Sheol, Nor will You allow Your Holy One to see corruption. You will show me the path of life; In Your presence is fullness of joy; At Your right hand are pleasures forevermore. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 19</title>
		<content>The heavens declare the glory of God; And the firmament shows His handiwork. Day unto day utters speech, And night unto night reveals knowledge. There is no speech nor language Where their voice is not heard. Their line has gone out through all the earth, And their words to the end of the world. In them He has set a tabernacle for the sun, Which is like a bridegroom coming out of his chamber, And rejoices like a strong man to run its race. Its rising is from one end of heaven, And its circuit to the other end; And there is nothing hidden from its heat.
            
The law of the LORD is perfect, converting the soul; The testimony of the LORD is sure, making wise the simple; The statutes of the LORD are right, rejoicing the heart; The commandment of the LORD is pure, enlightening the eyes; The fear of the LORD is clean, enduring forever; The judgments of the LORD are true and righteous altogether. More to be desired are they than gold, Yea, than much fine gold; Sweeter also than honey and the honeycomb. Moreover by them Your servant is warned, And in keeping them there is great reward.
            
Who can understand his errors? Cleanse me from secret faults. Keep back Your servant also from presumptuous sins; Let them not have dominion over me. Then I shall be blameless, And I shall be innocent of great transgression. Let the words of my mouth and the meditation of my heart Be acceptable in Your sight, O LORD, my strength and my redeemer. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 25</title>
		<content>To You, O LORD, I lift up my soul. O my God, I trust in You; Let me not be ashamed; Let not my enemies triumph over me. Indeed, let no one who waits on You be ashamed; Let those be ashamed who deal treacherously without cause. Show me Your ways, O LORD; Teach me Your paths. Lead me in Your truth and teach me, For You are the God of my salvation; On You I wait all the day.
            
Remember, O LORD, Your tender mercies and Your lovingkindnesses, For they have been from of old. Do not remember the sins of my youth, nor my transgressions; According to Your mercy remember me, For Your goodness’ sake, O LORD. Good and upright is the LORD; Therefore He teaches sinners in the way. The humble He guides in justice, And the humble He teaches His way. All the paths of the LORD are mercy and truth, To such as keep His covenant and His testimonies.
            
For Your name’s sake, O LORD, Pardon my iniquity, for it is great. Who is the man that fears the LORD? Him shall He teach in the way He chooses. He himself shall dwell in prosperity, And his descendants shall inherit the earth. The secret of the LORD is with those who fear Him, And He will show them His covenant. My eyes are ever toward the LORD, For He shall pluck my feet out of the net.
            
Turn Yourself to me, and have mercy on me, For I am desolate and afflicted. The troubles of my heart have enlarged; Oh, bring me out of my distresses! Look on my affliction and my pain, And forgive all my sins. Consider my enemies, for they are many; And they hate me with cruel hatred. Oh, keep my soul, and deliver me; Let me not be ashamed, for I put my trust in You. Let integrity and uprightness preserve me, For I wait for You. Redeem Israel, O God, Out of all their troubles! Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 27</title>
		<content>The LORD is my light and my salvation; Whom shall I fear? The LORD is the strength of my life; Of whom shall I be afraid? When the wicked came against me To eat up my flesh, My enemies and foes, They stumbled and fell.
            
Though an army should encamp against me, My heart shall not fear; Though war should rise against me, In this I will be confident. One thing I have desired of the LORD, That will I seek: That I may dwell in the house of the LORD All the days of my life, To behold the beauty of the LORD, And to inquire in His temple.
            
For in the time of trouble He shall hide me in His pavilion; In the secret place of His tabernacle He shall hide me; He shall set me high upon a rock. And now my head shall be lifted up above my enemies all around me; Therefore I will offer sacrifices of joy in His tabernacle; I will sing, yes, I will sing praises to the LORD. Hear, O LORD, when I cry with my voice! Have mercy also upon me, and answer me. When You said, “Seek My face,” My heart said to You, “Your face, LORD, I will seek.” Do not hide Your face from me; Do not turn Your servant away in anger; You have been my help; Do not leave me nor forsake me, O God of my salvation.
            
When my father and my mother forsake me, Then the LORD will take care of me. Teach me Your way, O LORD, And lead me in a smooth path, because of my enemies. Do not deliver me to the will of my adversaries; For false witnesses have risen against me, And such as breathe out violence. I would have lost heart, unless I had believed That I would see the goodness of the LORD In the land of the living. Wait on the LORD; Be of good courage, And He shall strengthen your heart; Wait, I say, on the LORD! Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 63</title>
		<content>O God, You are my God; Early will I seek You; My soul thirsts for You; My flesh longs for You In a dry and thirsty land Where there is no water. So I have looked for You in the sanctuary, To see Your power and Your glory. Because Your loving-kindness is better than life, My lips shall praise You. Thus I will bless You while I live; I will lift up my hands in Your name.
            
My soul shall be satisfied as with marrow and fatness, And my mouth shall praise You with joyful lips. When I remember You on my bed, I meditate on You in the night watches. Because You have been my help, Therefore in the shadow of Your wings I will rejoice.
            
My soul follows close behind You; Your right hand upholds me. But those who seek my life, to destroy it, Shall go into the lower parts of the earth. They shall fall by the sword; They shall be a portion for jackals. But the king shall rejoice in God; Everyone who swears by Him shall glory; But the mouth of those who speak lies shall be stopped. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 67</title>
		<content>God be merciful to us and bless us, And cause His face to shine upon us. That Your way may be known on earth, Your salvation among all nations. Let the peoples praise You, O God; Let all the peoples praise You.
            
Oh, let the nations be glad and sing for joy! For You shall judge the people righteously, And govern the nations on earth. Let the peoples praise You, O God; Let all the peoples praise You. Then the earth shall yield her increase; God, our own God, shall bless us. God shall bless us, And all the ends of the earth shall fear Him. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 70</title>
		<content>Make haste, O God, to deliver me! Make haste to help me, O LORD! Let them be ashamed and confounded Who seek my life; Let them be turned back and confused Who desire my hurt.
            
Let them be turned back because of their shame, Who say, “Aha, aha!” Let all those who seek You rejoice and be glad in You; And let those who love Your salvation say continually, “Let God be magnified!” But I am poor and needy; Make haste to me, O God! You are my help and my deliverer; O LORD, do not delay. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 113</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD! Praise, O servants of the LORD, Praise the name of the LORD! Blessed be the name of the LORD From this time forth and forevermore! From the rising of the sun to its going down The Lord’s name is to be praised.
            
The LORD is high above all nations, And His glory above the heavens. Who is like the LORD our God, Who dwells on high, Who humbles Himself to behold The things that are in the heavens and in the earth? He raises the poor out of the dust, And lifts the needy out of the ash heap, That He may seat him with princes—With the princes of His people. He grants the barren woman a home, Like a joyful mother of children. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Psalm 143</title>
		<content>Hear my prayer, O LORD, Give ear to my supplications! In Your faithfulness answer me, And in Your righteousness. Do not enter into judgment with Your servant, For in Your sight no one living is righteous. For the enemy has persecuted my soul; He has crushed my life to the ground; He has made me dwell in darkness, Like those who have long been dead.
            
Therefore my spirit is overwhelmed within me; My heart within me is distressed. I remember the days of old; I meditate on all Your works; I muse on the work of Your hands. I spread out my hands to You; My soul longs for You like a thirsty land. Answer me speedily, O LORD; My spirit fails! Do not hide Your face from me, Lest I be like those who go down into the pit.
            
Cause me to hear Your loving-kindness in the morning, For in You do I trust; Cause me to know the way in which I should walk, For I lift up my soul to You. Deliver me, O LORD, from my enemies; In You I take shelter. Teach me to do Your will, For You are my God; Your Spirit is good. Lead me in the land of uprightness.
            
Revive me, O LORD, for Your name’s sake! For Your righteousness’ sake bring my soul out of trouble. In Your mercy cut off my enemies, And destroy all those who afflict my soul; For I am Your servant. Alleluia.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>The Gospel (John 1:1-17)</title>
		<content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel according to St. John may his blessings be with us all. Amen.

In the beginning was the Word, and the Word was with God, and the Word was God. He was in the beginning with God. All things were made through Him, and without Him nothing was made that was made. In Him was life, and the life was the light of men.
            
And the light shines in the darkness, and the darkness did not comprehend it. There was a man sent from God, whose name was John. This man came for a witness, to bear witness of the Light, that all through him might believe. He was not that Light, but was sent to bear witness of that Light. That was the true Light which gives light to every man who comes into the world.
            
He was in the world, and the world was made through Him, and the world did not know Him. He came to His own, and His own did not receive Him. But as many as received Him, to them He gave the right to become children of God, even to those who believe in His name: who were born, not of blood, nor of the will of the flesh, nor of the will of man, but of God.
            
And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we beheld His glory, the glory as of the only begotten of the Father, full of grace and truth. John bore witness of Him and cried out, saying, “This was He of whom I said, ‘He who comes after me is preferred before me, for He was before me.’ ”
            
And of His fullness we have all received, and grace for grace. For the law was given through Moses, but grace and truth came through Jesus Christ.
            
Glory be to God forever. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Litanies</title>
        <content>O’ True Light, that enlightens every man, that comes into the world. You came to the world because of Your love to mankind, and all the creation rejoiced at Your coming. You saved our forefather Adam from temptation and our mother Eve from the pangs of death and granted us the spirit to be Your children - we praise You, we bless You saying;
            
Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty. (Glory be to the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.)
            
When the morning hour approaches, O’ Christ our God the True Light, let the senses and the thoughts of the light shine upon us, and let us not be covered by the darkness of pain that we may deeply praise You with David, saying: “My eyes are awake through the night, that I may meditate on Your word”. Listen to our voices according to Your great mercy, and save us, O’ Lord our God, through Your compassion.
            
Keneen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen. (Now and forever more. Amen.)
            
You are the honourable Mother of the light. Everywhere under the sun, people offer you glorification, the Mother of God (Theotokos), the second heaven. For you are the bright and unchangeable blossom, and the ever-virgin Mother, for the Father chose you, the Holy Spirit over shadowed you and the Son, in humility, was incarnated from you.
            
May you ask Him to redeem the world He has created, and deliver it from tribulations. Let us sing to Him a new hymn and bless Him, now and at all times and forever more. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Gloria</title>
        <content>Let us sing with the angels: Glory to God in the highest, peace on earth and goodwill towards men. We praise You, we bless You, we serve You, we worship You, we confess to You, we proclaim Your Glory, and we thank You, for Your great Glory.
            
O’ Lord, the Heavenly King, God the Father Almighty, and our Lord the only-begotten Son, Jesus Christ, and the Holy Spirit. O’ Lord, Lamb of God and Son of the Father, who takes away the sins of the world, have mercy upon us, accept our supplications, You, who sits at the right hand of the Father, have mercy upon us.
            
For You alone are Holy. You alone are the most high my Lord Jesus Christ with the Holy Spirit. Glory be to God the Father. Amen. I give You blessing daily, and praise Your Holy Name forever and ever. Amen. Since the night, my spirit seeks You early, O’ my God, for Your commandments are the light that shines on the earth.
            
Continually I pursue Your ways for You became a help to me. Early, My Lord, You shall hear my voice. Tomorrow, I stand before You and You shall see me.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Trisagion</title>
        <content>Holy God, Holy Almighty, Holy Immortal who was born of the Virgin, have mercy upon us.
            
Holy God, Holy Almighty, Holy Immortal who was crucified for our sake, have mercy upon us.
            
Holy God, Holy Almighty, Holy Immortal who arose from the dead and ascended to the heavens, have mercy upon us. Glory be to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit now and forever more Amen.
            
O’ Holy Trinity, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Lord, forgive us our sins.
            
O’ Lord, forgive us our trespasses.
            
O’ Lord forgive us our transgressions.
            
O’ God, be with those who are sick, heal them for the sake of Your Holy Name. O’ Lord repose the souls of those who have passed over to You. O’ Lord, who is without fault, have mercy upon us, support us and accept our prayers, for Thine is the glory, honour, and triple holiness. Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
            
O’ Lord make us worthy to pray thankfully; “Our Father, who art in heaven ...”</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Praises to St Mary</title>
        <content>Hail to St Mary, full of grace, the ever-virgin, Mother of God, Mother of Christ, may you lift our prayers to Your beloved Son to forgive our sins.
            
Hail to the Holy Virgin, Mother of the True Light, Christ our Lord, may You ask our Lord to have mercy upon our souls and forgive us our sins.
            
O’ Virgin Mary, Mother of God, who pleads for mankind, pray for the forgiveness of our sins before Christ to whom you gave birth.
            
Hail to you, O’ Virgin and true Queen, Hail to the pride of mankind, Mother of Emmanuel, remember us O’ Faithful Pleader, before our Lord Jesus Christ, may He forgive us our sins.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Intoduction to the Creed</title>
        <content>We honour you, Mother of True Light and glorify you, O’ Holy Virgin Mother of God, for you gave birth to the Saviour of the World. He came and saved our souls.
            
Glory to You, our Master and King Jesus Christ, Pride of the Apostles, Crown of the Martyrs, Joy of the righteous, Steadiness of the churches, Remission of sins. We preach the Holy Trinity, the One Divinity, whom we worship and honour. Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Creed</title>
        <content>Truly we believe in One God, the Almighty God the Father, maker of heaven and earth, of all things visible and invisible. We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ the only begotten Son of God, born of the Father before all ages; light out of light, true God out of true God, begotten not made; consubstantial with the Father, through whom all things came into being.
            
He descended from heaven for us and for our salvation, and was incarnated from the Holy Spirit and of the Virgin Mary, and became man. He was crucified for us at the time of Pontius Pilate. He suffered and was buried; arose from the dead on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures; He ascended to the heavens and sat at the right hand of the Father; He shall also come in His glory to judge the living and the dead; of whose kingdom there will be no end.
            
Truly we believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lifegiving Lord, who proceeds from the Father, we worship and glorify Him together with the Father and the Son, who spoke in the prophets. And in one, holy, universal and Apostolic Church. We acknowledge one baptism for the remission of sins. And we look for the resurrection of the dead and the life of the world to come. Amen.
            
            
Lord have mercy. (Kir-ye ley-son) 41 times.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Holy, Holy, Holy</title>
		<content>Holy, Holy, Holy is the Lord of hosts. Heaven and earth are full of Your glory and honour. God the Father Almighty, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity have mercy upon us. O’ Lord, God of hosts, be with us, for we have no other supporter in our tribulations and adversities but You. O’ God, absolve, remit and forgive us our sins which we have done willingly and unwillingly, and those which we committed knowingly and unknowingly, the hidden and the visible.
            
O’ Lord forgive us for the sake of Your Holy Name that is called upon us, and according to Your mercy and not to our sins. “Our Father, who art in heaven ...”</content>
    </prayer>
    
       <prayer>
        <title>The Absolution</title>
           <content>O’ Lord, God of hosts, existing before the ages and abiding forever, Who created the sun to light up the day, and the night to provide rest for all people. We thank You our eternal King, for You passed us through the night in peace and brought us to the beginning of this day.
               
Therefore we ask You, our King, may Your light shine upon us, and may You enlighten us with the light of Your divine knowledge. Make us children of light, children of daytime, that we may complete this day in righteousness, purity and good order and that we may complete the rest of our life without any blame, through the grace, compassion and love of mankind of Your Only-Begotten Son, Jesus Christ, and by the gift of the Holy Spirit, now and forever more. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Another Absolution</title>
        <content>O’ Giver of light, who makes the sun shine upon the righteous and the wicked; who created and gave light to the world, we ask You O’ Master of all, to enlighten our minds, hearts and understanding.
            
Grant us to please You this present day. Protect us from every evil, every sin and every enemy, through Jesus Christ our Lord, who is glorified with You and with the Holy Spirit giver of life, consubstantial Trinity, now and forever more. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>The Concluding Prayer</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon us O’ God, have mercy upon us. For You are always worshipped and glorified in heaven and on earth.
            
O’ Christ, our good Lord, plenteous in patience, mercy and compassion, who loves the just and shows mercy to all sinners amongst whom I am the first. Who does not wish death for the sinner but repentance and life, calling us all to salvation for the promised forthcoming rewards. O’ Lord, accept our prayers of this hour and every hour.
            
Ease our lives, and guide us to act according to Your commandments. Sanctify our souls, purify our bodies, set right our thoughts, cleanse our intentions, heal our sickness, forgive us our sins and deliver us from every evil grief and distress. Surround us with Your Holy angels that we may be guided and guarded with them to attain the unity of faith and knowledge of Your imperceptible and infinite glory, for You are blessed for ever. Amen.</content>
    </prayer>

</hour>

