<hour>
    <info><hourName>The Twelfth Hour</hourName><description>Instituted to commemorate the laying down of the body of our Lord Jesus Christ in the tomb, also because it is the last hour of man’s life in his day, since sleep is considered as a little death.</description>
    </info>
    <prayer>
		<title>Introductory Prayer</title>
		<content>† In the name of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, one God. Amen.
            
† Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
            
† Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit, now and forever and ever. Amen.
		</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Lord's Prayer</title>
		<content>O’ Lord make us worthy to pray thankfully:
            
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy Name. Thy Kingdom come. Thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us; and lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through Jesus Christ, our Lord, for Thine is the Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory forever. Amen.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Thanksgiving Prayer</title>
		<content>Let us give thanks to the gracious and merciful God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, for He has protected, assisted, preserved and accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.
            
Let us also ask Him the Almighty God, to keep us in peace this blessed day, and all the days of our life. O Lord, Master and Almighty God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, we thank You on every occasion, in every condition and for all things, for You have protected, assisted, preserved, accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.
            
Therefore, we ask and appeal to Your goodness, O Lover-of-mankind that You grant us to conclude this blessed day and all the days of our life in peace and in Your fear. All envy, all temptation, all works of Satan, all intrigues of the wicked; rising up of enemies, seen and unseen; do cast away from us and all your people, and from this Holy place.
            
Grant us the endowments and benefactions, as You have given us the authority to trample on serpents and scorpions, and over all the power of the enemy. Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through the grace, mercy and love of mankind of Your only begotten Son, our Lord God and Saviour, Jesus Christ. Glory, honour, dominion and worship are due to You together with Him and the Life-Giving and consubstantial Holy Spirit, now and forever. Amen.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 51</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon me, O God, According to Your loving-kindness; According to the multitude of Your tender mercies, Blot out my transgressions. Wash from my sin. For I acknowledge my transgressions, And my sin is ever before me. Against You, You only, have I sinned, And done this evil in Your sight—That You may be found just when You speak,And blameless when You judge.
            
Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity, And in sin my mother conceived me. Behold, You desire truth in the inward parts, And in the hidden part You will make me to know wisdom. Purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean; Wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow. Make me to hear joy and gladness, That the bones which You have broken may rejoice. Hide Your face from my sins, And blot out all my iniquities.
            
Create in me a clean heart, O God, And renew a steadfast spirit within me. Do not cast me away from Your presence, And do not take Your Holy Spirit from me. Restore to me the joy of Your salvation, And uphold me with Your generous Spirit. Then I will teach transgressors Your ways, And sinners shall be converted to You. Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, The God of my salvation, And my tongue shall sing aloud of Your righteousness.  O Lord, open my lips, And my mouth shall show forth Your praise. For You do not desire sacrifice, or else I would give it; You do not delight in burnt offering.
            
The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit, A broken and a contrite heart—These, O God, You will not despise. Do good in Your good pleasure to Zion; Build the walls of Jerusalem. Then You shall be pleased with the sacrifices of righteousness, With burnt offering and whole burnt offering; Then they shall offer bulls on Your altar. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<content>The Prayer of the Twelfth Hour of this blessed day is offered to Christ my King and my God, beseeching Him to forgive my sins.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 130</title>
		<content>Out of the depths I have cried to You, O LORD; LORD, hear my voice! Let Your ears be attentive To the voice of my supplications. If You, LORD, should mark iniquities, O Lord, who could stand? But there is forgiveness with You, That You may be feared.
            
I wait for the LORD, my soul waits, And in His word I do hope. My soul waits for the Lord More than those who watch for the morning—I say, more than those who watch for the morning. O Israel, hope in the LORD; For with the LORD there is mercy, And with Him is abundant redemption. And He shall redeem Israel From all his iniquities. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 131</title>
		<content>LORD, my heart is not haughty, Nor my eyes lofty. Neither do I concern myself with great matters, Nor with things too profound for me.
            
Surely I have calmed and quieted my soul, Like a weaned child with his mother; Like a weaned child is my soul within me. O Israel, hope in the LORD From this time forth and forever. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 132</title>
		<content>LORD, remember David And all his afflictions; How he swore to the LORD, And vowed to the Mighty God of Jacob: “Surely I will not go into the chamber of my house, Or go up to the comfort of my bed; I will not give sleep to my eyes Or slumber to my eyelids, Until I find a place for the LORD, A dwelling place for the Mighty God of Jacob.”
            
Behold, we heard of it in Ephrathah; We found it in the fields of the woods. Let us go into His tabernacle; Let us worship at His footstool. Arise, O LORD, to Your resting place, You and the ark of Your strength. Let Your priests be clothed with righteousness, And let Your saints shout for joy. For Your servant David’s sake, Do not turn away the face of Your Anointed.
            
The LORD has sworn in truth to David; He will not turn from it: “I will set upon your throne the fruit of your body. If your sons will keep My covenant And My testimony which I shall teach them, Their sons also shall sit upon your throne forevermore.” For the LORD has chosen Zion; He has desired it for His habitation: “This is My resting place forever; Here I will dwell, for I have desired it.
            
I will abundantly bless her provision; I will satisfy her poor with bread. I will also clothe her priests with salvation, And her saints shall shout aloud for joy. There I will make the horn of David grow; I will prepare a lamp for My Anointed. His enemies I will clothe with shame, But upon Himself His crown shall flourish.” Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 133</title>
		<content>Behold, how good and how pleasant it is For brethren to dwell together in unity! It is like the precious oil upon the head, Running down on the beard, The beard of Aaron, Running down on the edge of his garments.
            
It is like the dew of Hermon, Descending upon the mountains of Zion; For there the LORD commanded the blessing—Life for evermore. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 134</title>
		<content>Behold, bless the LORD, All you servants of the LORD, Who by night stand in the house of the LORD! Lift up your hands in the sanctuary, And bless the LORD. The LORD who made heaven and earth Bless you from Zion! Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 137</title>
		<content>By the rivers of Babylon, There we sat down, yea, we wept When we remembered Zion. We hung our harps Upon the willows in the midst of it. For there those who carried us away captive required of us a song, And those who plundered us required of us mirth, Saying, “Sing us one of the songs of Zion!” How shall we sing the Lord’s song In a foreign land?
            
If I forget you, O Jerusalem, Let my right hand forget her skill! If I do not remember you, Let my tongue cling to the roof of my mouth—If I do not exalt Jerusalem Above my chief joy. Remember, O LORD, against the sons of Edom The day of Jerusalem, Who said, “Raze it, raze it, To its very foundation!”
            
O daughter of Babylon, who are to be destroyed, Happy shall he be who repays you as you have served us! Happy shall he be who takes and dashes Your little ones against the rock. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 138</title>
		<content>I will praise You with my whole heart; Before the gods I will sing praises to You. I will worship toward Your holy temple, And praise Your name For Your loving-kindness and Your truth; For You have magnified Your word above all Your name.
            
In the day when I cried out, You answered me, And made me bold with strength in my soul. All the kings of the earth shall praise You, O LORD, When they hear the words of Your mouth. Yes, they shall sing of the ways of the LORD, For great is the glory of the LORD.
            
Though the LORD is on high, Yet He regards the lowly; But the proud He knows from afar. Though I walk in the midst of trouble, You will revive me; You will stretch out Your hand Against the wrath of my enemies, And Your right hand will save me. The LORD will perfect that which concerns me; Your mercy, O LORD, endures forever; Do not forsake the works of Your hands. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 141</title>
		<content>LORD, I cry out to You; Make haste to me! Give ear to my voice when I cry out to You. Let my prayer be set before You as incense, The lifting up of my hands as the evening sacrifice.
            
Set a guard, O LORD, over my mouth; Keep watch over the door of my lips. Do not incline my heart to any evil thing, To practice wicked works With men who work iniquity; And do not let me eat of their delicacies. Let the righteous strike me; It shall be a kindness.
            
And let him reprove me; It shall be as excellent oil; Let my head not refuse it. For still my prayer is against the deeds of the wicked. Their judges are overthrown by the sides of the cliff, And they hear my words, for they are sweet.
            
Our bones are scattered at the mouth of the grave, As when one ploughs and breaks up the earth. But my eyes are upon You, O God the Lord; In You I take refuge; Do not leave my soul destitute. Keep me from the snares which they have laid for me, And from the traps of the workers of iniquity. Let the wicked fall into their own nets, While I escape safely. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 142</title>
		<content>I cry out to the LORD with my voice; With my voice to the LORD I make my supplication. I pour out my complaint before Him; I declare before Him my trouble. When my spirit was overwhelmed within me, Then You knew my path. In the way in which I walk They have secretly set a snare for me.
            
Look on my right hand and see, For there is no one who acknowledges me; Refuge has failed me; No one cares for my soul. I cried out to You, O LORD: I said, “You are my refuge, My portion in the land of the living. Attend to my cry, For I am brought very low; Deliver me from my persecutors, For they are stronger than I.
            
Bring my soul out of prison, That I may praise Your name; The righteous shall surround me, For You shall deal bountifully with me.” Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 146</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD! Praise the LORD, O my soul! While I live I will praise the LORD; I will sing praises to my God while I have my being. Do not put your trust in princes, Nor in a son of man, in whom there is no help.
            
His spirit departs, he returns to his earth; In that very day his plans perish. Happy is he who has the God of Jacob for his help, Whose hope is in the LORD his God, Who made heaven and earth, The sea, and all that is in them; Who keeps truth forever, Who executes justice for the oppressed, Who gives food to the hungry.
            
The LORD gives freedom to the prisoners. The LORD opens the eyes of the blind; The LORD raises those who are bowed down; The LORD loves the righteous. The LORD watches over the strangers; He relieves the fatherless and widow; But the way of the wicked He turns upside down. The LORD shall reign forever—Your God, O Zion, to all generations. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 147:1-11</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD! For it is good to sing praises to our God; For it is pleasant, and praise is beautiful. The LORD builds up Jerusalem; He gathers together the outcasts of Israel. He heals the broken-hearted And binds up their wounds.
            
He counts the number of the stars; He calls them all by name. Great is our Lord, and mighty in power; His understanding is infinite. The LORD lifts up the humble; He casts the wicked down to the ground. Sing to the LORD with thanksgiving; Sing praises on the harp to our God, Who covers the heavens with clouds, Who prepares rain for the earth, Who makes grass to grow on the mountains.
            
He gives to the beast its food, And to the young ravens that cry. He does not delight in the strength of the horse; He takes no pleasure in the legs of a man. The LORD takes pleasure in those who fear Him, In those who hope in His mercy. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 147:12-20</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD, O Jerusalem! Praise your God, O Zion! For He has strengthened the bars of your gates; He has blessed your children within you. He makes peace in your borders, And fills you with the finest wheat.
            
He sends out His command to the earth; His word runs very swiftly. He gives snow like wool; He scatters the frost like ashes; He casts out His hail like morsels; Who can stand before His cold? He sends out His word and melts them; He causes His wind to blow, and the waters flow.
            
He declares His word to Jacob, His statutes and His judgments to Israel. He has not dealt thus with any nation; And as for His judgments, they have not known them. Alleluia.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Gospel (Luke 2:25-32)</title>
		<content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel according to St. Luke may his blessings be with us all. Amen.
            
And behold, there was a man in Jerusalem whose name was Simeon, and this man was just and devout, waiting for the Consolation of Israel, and the Holy Spirit was upon him. And it had been revealed to him by the Holy Spirit that he would not see death before he had seen the Lord’s Christ.
            
So he came by the Spirit into the temple. And when the parents brought in the Child Jesus, to do for Him according to the custom of the law, he took Him up in his arms and blessed God and said: “Lord, now You are letting Your servant depart in peace, according to Your word; for my eyes have seen Your salvation which You have prepared before the face of all peoples, a light to bring revelation to the Gentiles, and the glory of Your people Israel.” Glory be to God forever. Amen.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Litanies</title>
		<content>Behold, I am about to stand before the just judge in fear because of my numerous sins, for the life spent in pleasures deserves condemnation. Repent therefore, O my soul so long as you dwell on earth, for the dust in the grave offers no praise, and amongst the dead no one remembers, nor those who are in Hades, give thanks. Rise up from your laziness and implore the Saviour in repentance, saying; Lord have mercy upon me and save me.
            
Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty.
            
If this life was everlasting and this world eternal, O my soul, you would have a valid excuse. But if your wicked deeds and repulsive evils are exposed before the just judge, what answer would you give when you are lying on the bed of sin and failed to subject the body. O’ Christ, our God, before Your fearful throne of judgement I am terrified, and before Your counsel of judgment I am in awe, and unto the light of Your divinity I tremble, I am the wicked and defiled, lying on my bed careless about my life. Yet I imitate the tax-collector beating on my chest saying; “God be merciful to me a sinner”
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
            
O’ Pure virgin, cast the shadow of your assistance on your servant. Remove the evil thoughts and raise my frail soul to stay awake and pray, because it has been lying long in deep sleep. You are a capable, merciful and helpful Mother, the Mother of the Spring of life, my King and God, Jesus Christ, my hope. Lord, by Your grace protect us this night from sin. You are the blessed God of our fathers, Your Holy name is full of glory forever. Amen.
            
Lord, let Your mercy on us be as great as our reliance on You, because all eyes are focused upon You. You give us food in due time. Hear us, our Lord and Saviour, because You are the hope of the world, You alone are able to protect and save us from this generation and even unto eternity. Amen.
            
Blessed are You, Lord, teach me Your justice, show me Your will, enlighten me to Your goodness. Your mercy is everlasting, do not reject what You have made with Your own hands because You are my refuge from generation to generation. I cried to the Lord: “I have sinned against You, have mercy upon me and save my soul”. Save me Lord, for I am seeking You. Teach me to do Your will, for You are my Lord, You have the spring of life, through Your light we see light, let Your mercy come to those who know You and Your goodness to those who are pure in heart.
            
Blessing, praise and glory are due to You, O’ Father and Son and Holy Spirit who is being since the beginning, now, and forever. Amen. It is good to confess to the Lord and to praise Your name, O Most High, Your mercy are declared in the mornings and Your justice every night.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Trisagion</title>
		<content>Holy God, Holy Almighty, Holy Immortal who was born of the Virgin, have mercy upon us.
            
Holy God, Holy Almighty, Holy Immortal who was crucified for our sake, have mercy upon us.
            
Holy God, Holy Almighty, Holy Immortal who arose from the dead and ascended to the heavens, have mercy upon us.
            
Glory be to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit now and forever more Amen.
            
O’ Holy Trinity, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Lord, forgive us our sins.
            
O’ Lord, forgive us our trespasses.
            
O’ Lord forgive us our transgressions.
            
O’ God, be with those who are sick, heal them for the sake of Your Holy Name. O’ Lord repose the souls of those who have passed over to You. O’ Lord, who is without fault, have mercy upon us, support us and accept our prayers, for Thine is the glory, honour, and triple holiness. Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
            
O’ Lord make us worthy to pray thankfully; “Our Father, who art in heaven ...”
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
        <title>Praises to St Mary</title>
        <content>Hail to St Mary, full of grace, the ever-virgin, Mother of God, Mother of Christ, may you lift our prayers to Your beloved Son to forgive our sins.
            
Hail to the Holy Virgin, Mother of the True Light, Christ our Lord, may You ask our Lord to have mercy upon our souls and forgive us our sins.
            
O’ Virgin Mary, Mother of God, who pleads for mankind, pray for the forgiveness of our sins before Christ to whom you gave birth.
            
Hail to you, O’ Virgin and true Queen, Hail to the pride of mankind, Mother of Emmanuel, remember us O’ Faithful Pleader, before our Lord Jesus Christ, may He forgive us our sins.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>Intoduction to the Creed</title>
        <content>We honour you, Mother of True Light and glorify you, O’ Holy Virgin Mother of God, for you gave birth to the Saviour of the World. He came and saved our souls.
            
Glory to You, our Master and King Jesus Christ, Pride of the Apostles, Crown of the Martyrs, Joy of the righteous, Steadiness of the churches, Remission of sins. We preach the Holy Trinity, the One Divinity, whom we worship and honour. Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
    <prayer>
        <title>The Creed</title>
        <content>Truly we believe in One God, the Almighty God the Father, maker of heaven and earth, of all things visible and invisible. We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ the only begotten Son of God, born of the Father before all ages; light out of light, true God out of true God, begotten not made; consubstantial with the Father, through whom all things came into being.
            
He descended from heaven for us and for our salvation, and was incarnated from the Holy Spirit and of the Virgin Mary, and became man. He was crucified for us at the time of Pontius Pilate. He suffered and was buried; arose from the dead on the third day in accordance with the Scriptures; He ascended to the heavens and sat at the right hand of the Father; He shall also come in His glory to judge the living and the dead; of whose kingdom there will be no end.
            
Truly we believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lifegiving Lord, who proceeds from the Father, we worship and glorify Him together with the Father and the Son, who spoke in the prophets. And in one, holy, universal and Apostolic Church. We acknowledge one baptism for the remission of sins. And we look for the resurrection of the dead and the life of the world to come. Amen.
            
Lord have mercy. (Kir-ye ley-son) 41 times.
        </content>
    </prayer>
    
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Holy, Holy, Holy</title>
		<content>Holy, Holy, Holy is the Lord of hosts. Heaven and earth are full of Your glory and honour. God the Father Almighty, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity have mercy upon us. O’ Lord, God of hosts, be with us, for we have no other supporter in our tribulations and adversities but You. O’ God, absolve, remit and forgive us our sins which we have done willingly and unwillingly, and those which we committed knowingly and unknowingly, the hidden and the visible.
            
O’ Lord forgive us for the sake of Your Holy Name that is called upon us, and according to Your mercy and not to our sins.
            
“Our Father, who art in heaven ...”
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Absolution</title>
		<content>For the sake of Your Holy name, Lord, for Your goodness and love to mankind, forgive us those sins we committed against You this day, whether they are by action, by words, by thought or any of our senses.
            
Grant us a peaceful night and give us a sleep free of all anxiety, send us the guardian angel to protect us from every evil, temptation or the strike of the enemy, through the grace, mercy and love of Your Son, our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. Together with Him and the life-giving and consubstantial Holy Spirit You are worthy of glory, honour and dominion for ever and ever. Amen.
		 </content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Concluding Prayer</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon us O’ God, have mercy upon us. For You are always worshipped and glorified in heaven and on earth.
            
O’ Christ, our good Lord, plenteous in patience, mercy and compassion, who loves the just and shows mercy to all sinners amongst whom I am the first. Who does not wish death for the sinner but repentance and life, calling us all to salvation for the promised forthcoming rewards. O’ Lord, accept our prayers of this hour and every hour.
            
Ease our lives, and guide us to act according to Your commandments. Sanctify our souls, purify our bodies, set right our thoughts, cleanse our intentions, heal our sickness, forgive us our sins and deliver us from every evil grief and distress. Surround us with Your Holy angels that we may be guided and guarded with them to attain the unity of faith and knowledge of Your imperceptible and infinite glory, for You are blessed for ever. Amen.
        </content>
	</prayer>
</hour>  