<hour>
    <info>
    	<hourName>Other Prayers</hourName>
    	<description>A collection of prayers that are read in their applicable time</description>
        <time>A collection of prayers</time>
        
    </info>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>Prayer Before Holy Communion</title>
		<content>Lord, I am not worthy to have You come under my roof because I am a sinner, but only say the word; “Your sins are forgiven” and my soul will be healed. I am barren and empty of any goodness, I have nothing but Your compassion, mercy and love to mankind.

You descended from your Heavenly Glory to our humility and consented to be born in a Manger. O’ Holy Saviour, do not reject my humble and miserable soul which is waiting for Your Glorified coming. As You did not refuse to enter the leper’s house to heal him, please Lord, come into my soul to cleanse it.
            
As You did not stop the adulteress from kissing Your feet, please do not prevent me from coming near You to receive Your Holy Body and Your Sacred Blood. May this Holy Communion banish every corruption and mortify all my evil desires.
            
Help me to obey Your commandments and heal my soul and my body from every sin. May Your spirit dwell with in me and make me united with You so I may live for the Glory of Your Name. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
        
		<title>Prayer After Holy Communion</title>
		<content>My tongue praises and my soul glorifies the Lord. My heart rejoices for You have come to me, Lord, and dressed me in purity and allowed me to Your feast. May my union with You today be everlasting, through it I grow in strength of faith and hope.
            
Let my communion be a symbol of the grace of Your salvation, let it be a purification to my body and my soul and preparation for the everlasting love and joy. To You Lord, I surrender myself and my will, call to You my senses and bless them and let my mind to be according to Your will.
            
Enlighten my heart, awaken my conscience, cast away all shadows of evil, hush the storms, walk with me and guide me. Give me comfort, quench my thirst, look with love at all my short comings, abide with me for the day is coming to an end and stay with me for a new day. You alone are my aim and happiness, now and forever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>

    
    <prayer>
		<title>Prayer of Repentance</title>         
		<content>My Lord God and Saviour Jesus Christ, treasure of mercy and spring of salvation, I come to You confessing my sins. I confess that, insolently, I dared to defile Your Holy Sanctuary with my sins. Now I seek Your mercy and love, for Your mercies are boundless; You never turn back a sinner who comes back to You.
            
I confess that my mind is burdened with sin and that I have no strength left. Do not turn away from me, do not rebuke me in Your anger nor chasten me in Your hot displeasure. I am worn out, have compassion upon me, O’ Lord do not judge me in Your justice, but according to Your mercy.
            
Remember Your creation, do not put me on trial, because none of Your servants can justify his deeds. Dress me in a new attire that befits Your glory. Forgive my sins and I shall sing; “Blessed is he whose sins are forgiven.” When I confess my sins, and reveal my iniquities, You cleanse them. Amen.</content>
	</prayer> 
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer Before Confession</title>         
		<content>O Holy Father who awaits the return of sinners, You gave Your promise that You are ready to accept those who repent. Look now to a soul that was lost in the valleys of disobedience. For a long time I have tasted the bitterness of misery, being away from the stream of salvation.
            
Now I come back to You to be purified, accept and not reject me, for when you look at me with mercy and compassion, I will be cleansed and saved. If you turn away, I shall perish. Grant me O Lord, Your blessing to strengthen my will to come closer to You in faith and hope, to confess my sins and detest returning to them.
            
May Your Holy Spirit remind me not to stray. May You enlighten my heart so I can see the graveness of my sins and negligence and have the will to obey Your commandments and live for the Glory of Your Holy Name. Amen.</content>
	</prayer> 

	<prayer>
	      <title>Prayer After Confession</title>         
		<content>O’ Father, I am grateful for Your goodness, and love for mankind. You did not wish that I perish, but awakened me from my sleep and guided me to Your path. You saved me from the valley of death to the protection of Your strong fortress.
            
Fill me with hope and faith, I come to You like the sick wishing to be healed, like the hungry seeking to be filled, like the thirsty to the springs of living water, like the poor to the source of riches and the sinner to the redeemer, and like the dying to the origin of life. You are my salvation, my health, my life and my strength.
            
With You, I find consolation, happiness and comfort. Help me, protect me and surround me with Your goodness. Teach me to put my will in Your hands and live according to Your will. Remove my weakness so I may be firm and honest to You to the end. Amen.</content>
	</prayer> 
	
    
		
	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer Before Meals</title>         
		<content>Blessed are you O’ Lord who supports us from our youth: grants us Your blessings, and provides food for all; for our eyes are focused upon you. You give us our food in due course. You open your hands and fill every living creature.
            
To you is the glory, praise, blessing and thanksgiving for the food that you have prepared for us. Stretch your hand and bless the food set before us for the nourishment of our bodies. Let it be strength and health to our lives. Grant salvation, grace, blessing and purity to all those who partake of it.
            
Lift our minds to you at all times to seek our spiritual and eternal food. Give us to labour for the food which endures to everlasting life. Grant us to be partakers in your heavenly feast. Give us the bread of blessing, the cup of salvation and fill our hearts with joy and gladness. Grant us a quiet peaceful life, a joyful soul and a healthy body.
            
Teach us to seek your acceptance in everything so that if we eat, drink or make anything, we do it for the glory of Your Holy Name. For thine is the glory forever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer> 
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Prayer for God’s Guidance</title>         
		<content>Lord You are aware that I do not know what is good for me, and now that I am about to start .........., how can I know if it is right unless You guide me with Your grace. O’ Lord, I beseech Your guidance in this matter, do not let me follow my tendencies, lest I will be confused and fall, keep me from slipping, help me, let it be according to Your will.
            
If You see it fit, grant me Your blessing to complete it, if not, remove this desire from my heart. You know all things, nothing is concealed from You. Lord, I am Your servant, deal with me as You see fit as I realise that I will have neither success nor peace unless I submit my self to the grace of Your will, teach me to say in every occasion; “Let it be according to Your will, Lord, not according to mine.” For Yours is the Kingdom, the Power and Glory forever more. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
    
    <prayer>
		<title>The Priest's Absolution</title>
		<content>We thank and entreat You, O Master and Lord Jesus Christ the Son of the Living God, the Eternal, abiding in the light before all ages, Light out of Light; enlighten, O Lord, our minds and our hearts, and illuminate our understanding, so that we understand Your life-giving words. Raise us from the darkness of sin which kills the soul.
            
Make us worthy to be steadfast in good and beneficial works. At the time of Your awesome second coming, when you will judge the world, may we be worthy of hearing that voice which is full of happiness, joy, consolation, delight and grace from Your divine mouth, saying: “Come to Me, you blessed of My Father, inherit the kingdom which was prepared for you since the creation of the world”.
            
Yes, O Lord our God, fit us to be, on that day and in that hour, without fear, without fault, without disturbance, without failure and without deviation. Do not deal with us O Lord according to the multitude of our sins. Pardon O Lord, all our vices, faults, mistakes and lapses. Relieve us, and the whole world, O Lord, from death, inflation, plagues, destruction, eviction, the sword of enemies, the plots of demons, the danger of fire and drowning, the opposition of those who are evil, the intrigues of the shameless and the injustice of judges.
            
Bring to failure the works of the stubborn against us. For You are our Lord and God, have compassion on us. Do not cast us into the sea of destruction nor to the punishment of our ways. But rescue us, protect us, preserve us and raise us from boredom, anger, languishing, and laziness.
            
Do not let the enemy - the devil - overwhelm us with excessive hope, but alert our minds and awaken our hearts from the sleep of inattention and wasting our lifetime in vain. O God, disregard our trespasses and forgive us our lapses, do not remember our sins or our vices, do not be angry with us and may Your anger not continue forever.
            
Have mercy on us O Lord, have mercy on us, for we are weak and poor, drowning in the ocean of sin. Unto You we cry out; before You we bow; by You we confess; it is You whom we want. Do not cut off our hope my Master, in Your mercy, and do not close the door of Your mercy in our faces. But out of Your goodness save us; lead us to Your mercy, and let us hear Your joyful voice.
            
O God, purify us and purify our hearts from wicked, unclean and bad thoughts. Remove from us, O Lord, and from Your people, all dreams, fancies and devilish ideas. Raise us O God, from every fall and catastrophe. Establish in us O God, patience, hope, love and orthodox faith. Count us among the sheep at Your right hand.
            
Seat us with those who recline in Your heavenly banquet. Forgive us for every trespass, guilt and sin; protect us in the fortress of Your luminous, angelic soldiers. For we have no salvation except through Your mercy. Our reliance is on You, our faith is in You and our hope is in You. Accept from us O Lord, our supplications at this present time and at all times.
            
And all those who asked and directed us to remember them in prayers, liturgies, unctions of the sick and commemorations; whether alive or dead; remember us O Lord, together with them, with kindness in the heavenly Jerusalem, in the Kingdom of Heaven. Blot out O Lord, our vices, and those who offended us, forgive them and us.
            
Through Your mercy O Lord, save all our souls. O Lord, save Your people, bless Your inheritance, shepherd and guide them forever. Save those who are in hardships, distresses and sadness. Free those who are bound from the bonds of devils. Satisfy the hungry with good things. Console the small in heart and spirit. Raise the fallen; make steadfast those who have risen. Restore the lost. Take care of the widow and the orphan. Aid the needy.
            
Give blessings to the fruits of the earth, grant that the weather be favourable, give growth to the plants, raise the waters of the rivers fully and bless the dew and the rains. Give contentment to those in need. Repay for those in debt. Gather together the fragments which are divided. Accept the repentance of the penitent.
            
Accept the confession of the confessors. Give understanding to the catechumens. Give fair judgment O Lord, to the oppressed. Fill our hearts with joy, happiness, comfort, delight and grace, so that as we have sufficiency in all things, we excel in acceptable good works. Bless O Lord, the crops with heavenly blessings.
            
Bless O Lord the crown of this year with Your goodness. Bless O Lord the sower, the cultivator, the planter and the reaper, as You blessed the crops of the children of Israel in the sixth year. Bless O Lord this gathering of ours, and all the gatherings of orthodox people. Preserve for us the life and the reign of our father and Patriarch Pope ..., the Patriarch of this time.
            
Save him O Lord and save his people from all catastrophes, trials and sorrows. And also his partners in the apostolic ministry, our fathers the Metropolitans, our fathers the Bishops, our fathers the Hegumens and our fathers the Priests, our brothers the Deacons, our fathers the Monks, our brothers the laymen and those who came, attended and shared with us in this prayer and all the prayers of the orthodox, now asking for the forgiveness of their sins and mercy for their souls.
            
Bless us and bless them; absolve us and absolve them; forgive our sins and their sins, those passed and those we might return to, those personal and those not personal, those by night ~d those by day, those manifest and those hidden. Preserve O Lord, the welfare of the assemblies, the holy churches, the orthodox wilderness, and the elders who dwell in them, its servants, its overseers, and those who are in it.
            
Grant security, peace, love and reassurance to be among them. Bring down the evil enemy under our feet and their feet. Do not let him have any part in us or in them, neither by the left hand blow nor by the right hand blow, but preserve them with Your exalted hand and Your protective arm. Rescue us my Master, from evil temptations and from the snares set, the visible and the invisible.
            
Remember O Lord, our fathers, our mothers, our brothers and our sisters, our families, our relatives, our teachers, our spiritual children, our children in the flesh and all the children of Baptism together. Remember O Lord, those through whose toil and effort we have eaten and drunk, have sheltered us in their houses and gave us from their hands.
            
Repay them O Lord and compensate them with the eternal for the temporal and the heavenly for the earthly. Fill their houses and their stores with every good thing. Repay them O Lord, thirty fold, sixty fold and a hundredfold, and the forgiveness of their sins in the Kingdom of Heaven. Remember O Lord, those who have done good unto us and to our poor brethren, with every kind of good work, in love for You and honour for Your Holy Name, and bless them.
            
Remember O Lord, those who are concerned with the sacrifices, offerings, burnt offerings, wine, oil, first fruits, incense, curtains, vows, books of readings and all the utensils of the altar generally. Repay them O Lord, for what they have given, with the forgiveness of their sins. Grant them in this present age a pleasant life and in the coming age eternal life.
            
Remember O Lord our fathers and brethren who have departed, reposed and rested with faith in Christ. Repose O Lord, all their souls, in the embrace of our holy fathers, Abraham, Isaac and Jacob, in the place of the living, in the Paradise of Joy. As for us who are still alive, aid us to find salvation for our souls, arrange our lives according to Your gracious will.
            
Please O Lord, remember my insignificance, my humiliation, my weakness, I the sinner who am troubled, and unworthy of standing between Your hands. Because of the multitude of my sins and guilt, do not reject me. Erect O Lord, a horn of salvation for Your people through the sign of Your life-giving Cross. We ask Your relief in hardships and Your aid in misery and humiliation.
            
Save us O Lord and save everyone in hardships. Those of Your people who are sick, heal them. Grant O Lord, Your people the Christians, those present with us and those absent from us, that they may be blessed and absolved from Your Divine mouth, from the rising of the to its setting, and from the north to the south.
            
Accept us unto You, as You accepted the right-hand thief when You were on the Cross, and granted him the Paradise of Joy. Remember O Lord, the orphans and the widows, the estranged, the disabled and those who have no one to remember them. Remember us O Lord, with them, in the heavenly Jerusalem. Remember O Lord those standing or sitting, sleeping or lying in illness, those who are travelling by land, sea, air, on plains, by rough roads, through valleys, narrow ways, on mountain peaks and hills, in caves, those who are in gaols or prisons, those who are in captivity and exiled, the captives and those who are bound with the bonds of wicked powers and of demons.
            
Return them and bring them all to their ports safely, profitably and healthy in soul, body and spirit. Grant O my Lord Jesus Christ, that these our prayers may be accepted before You without hypocrisy, pride, haughtiness, being puffed up or any fault. Aid us O God in doing Your will. Aid us in performing Your commandments. Aid us in the pangs of death, and that which is before death and that which is after death.
            
For You are a righteous God, long suffering, plenteous in mercy and compassion. O Lord grant that the door of Your Church be open before us through the ages of ages and unto the end of time. Have mercy upon us O God, according to the multitude of Your mercy.
            
Through the intercessions of the Lady of intercession, the essence of purity, generosity and blessings; our Lady and the pride of our race, the chaste Virgin, the blameless St Mary, and the honoured martyr, St Mark the evangelist, apostle and preacher of the land of Egypt, and all the angels, the fathers, the prophets, the apostles, the martyrs, the saints, the spiritborne, the worshipers, the ascetics, the strivers and those who have pleased the Lord with their good works, from Adam, to the end of ages. To You, we bow down O Holy Trinity, Father, Son and Holy Spirit, now and at all times, and unto the ages of ages. Amen</content>
    </prayer>
	
	 </hour>  