<hour>
    <info><hourName>The Ninth Hour</hourName>
        <description>Instituted to commemorate the hour of death of our Lord Jesus Christ in the flesh, and the right-hand thief who found favour in His eyes.</description>
    </info>
    <prayer>
		<title>Introductory Prayer</title>
		<content>† In the name of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, one God. Amen.
            
† Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
            
† Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit, now and forever and ever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Lord's Prayer</title>
		<content>O’ Lord make us worthy to pray thankfully:
            
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy Name. Thy Kingdom come. Thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us; and lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through Jesus Christ, our Lord, for Thine is the Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory forever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Thanksgiving Prayer</title>
		<content>Let us give thanks to the gracious and merciful God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, for He has protected, assisted, preserved and accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.
            
Let us also ask Him the Almighty God, to keep us in peace this blessed day, and all the days of our life. O Lord, Master and Almighty God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, we thank You on every occasion, in every condition and for all things, for You have protected, assisted, preserved, accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.
            
Therefore, we ask and appeal to Your goodness, O Lover-of-mankind that You grant us to conclude this blessed day and all the days of our life in peace and in Your fear. All envy, all temptation, all works of Satan, all intrigues of the wicked; rising up of enemies, seen and unseen; do cast away from us and all your people, and from this Holy place.
            
Grant us the endowments and benefactions, as You have given us the authority to trample on serpents and scorpions, and over all the power of the enemy. Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through the grace, mercy and love of mankind of Your only begotten Son, our Lord God and Saviour, Jesus Christ. Glory, honour, dominion and worship are due to You together with Him and the Life-Giving and consubstantial Holy Spirit, now and forever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 51</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon me, O God, According to Your loving-kindness; According to the multitude of Your tender mercies, Blot out my transgressions. Wash from my sin. For I acknowledge my transgressions, And my sin is ever before me. Against You, You only, have I sinned, And done this evil in Your sight—That You may be found just when You speak,And blameless when You judge.
            
Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity, And in sin my mother conceived me. Behold, You desire truth in the inward parts, And in the hidden part You will make me to know wisdom. Purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean; Wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow. Make me to hear joy and gladness, That the bones which You have broken may rejoice. Hide Your face from my sins, And blot out all my iniquities.
            
Create in me a clean heart, O God, And renew a steadfast spirit within me. Do not cast me away from Your presence, And do not take Your Holy Spirit from me. Restore to me the joy of Your salvation, And uphold me with Your generous Spirit. Then I will teach transgressors Your ways, And sinners shall be converted to You. Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, The God of my salvation, And my tongue shall sing aloud of Your righteousness.  O Lord, open my lips, And my mouth shall show forth Your praise. For You do not desire sacrifice, or else I would give it; You do not delight in burnt offering.
            
The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit, A broken and a contrite heart—These, O God, You will not despise. Do good in Your good pleasure to Zion; Build the walls of Jerusalem. Then You shall be pleased with the sacrifices of righteousness, With burnt offering and whole burnt offering; Then they shall offer bulls on Your altar. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<content>The Prayer of the Ninth Hour of this blessed day is offered to Christ my King and my God, beseeching Him to forgive my sins.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 96</title>
		<content>Oh, sing to the LORD a new song! Sing to the LORD, all the earth. Sing to the LORD, bless His name; Proclaim the good news of His salvation from day to day. Declare His glory among the nations, His wonders among all peoples. For the LORD is great and greatly to be praised; He is to be feared above all gods.
            
For all the gods of the peoples are idols, But the LORD made the heavens. Honour and majesty are before Him; Strength and beauty are in His sanctuary. Give to the LORD, O kindreds of the peoples, Give to the LORD glory and strength. Give to the LORD the glory due His name; Bring an offering, and come into His courts.
            
Oh, worship the LORD in the beauty of holiness! Tremble before Him, all the earth. Say among the nations, “The LORD reigns; The world also is firmly established, It shall not be moved; He shall judge the peoples righteously.”
            
Let the heavens rejoice, and let the earth be glad; Let the sea roar, and all its fullness; Let the field be joyful, and all that is in it. Then all the trees of the woods will rejoice before the LORD. For He is coming, for He is coming to judge the earth. He shall judge the world with righteousness, And the peoples with His truth. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 97</title>
		<content>The LORD reigns; Let the earth rejoice; Let the multitude of isles be glad! Clouds and darkness surround Him; Righteousness and justice are the foundation of His throne. A fire goes before Him, And burns up His enemies round about. His lightnings light the world; The earth sees and trembles.
            
The mountains melt like wax at the presence of the LORD, At the presence of the Lord of the whole earth. The heavens declare His righteousness, And all the peoples see His glory. Let all be put to shame who serve carved images, Who boast of idols. Worship Him, all you gods. Zion hears and is glad, And the daughters of Judah rejoice Because of Your judgments, O LORD. For You, LORD, are most high above all the earth; You are exalted far above all gods.
            
You who love the LORD, hate evil! He preserves the souls of His saints; He delivers them out of the hand of the wicked. Light is sown for the righteous, And gladness for the upright in heart. Rejoice in the LORD, you righteous, And give thanks at the remembrance of his holy name. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 98</title>
		<content>Oh, sing to the LORD a new song! For He has done marvellous things; His right hand and His holy arm have gained Him the victory. The LORD has made known His salvation; His righteousness He has openly shown in the sight of the nations. He has remembered His mercy and His faithfulness to the house of Israel; All the ends of the earth have seen the salvation of our God.
            
Shout joyfully to the LORD, all the earth; Break forth in song, rejoice, and sing praises. Sing to the LORD with the harp, With the harp and the sound of a psalm, With trumpets and the sound of a horn; Shout joyfully before the LORD, the King. Let the sea roar, and all its fullness, The world and those who dwell in it; Let the rivers clap their hands; Let the hills be joyful together before the LORD, For He is coming to judge the earth. With righteousness He shall judge the world, And the peoples with equity. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 99</title>
		<content>The LORD reigns; Let the peoples tremble! He dwells between the cherubim; Let the earth be moved! The LORD is great in Zion, And He is high above all the peoples. Let them praise Your great and awesome name—He is holy.
            
The King’s strength also loves justice; You have established equity; You have executed justice and righteousness in Jacob. Exalt the LORD our God, And worship at His footstool; For He is holy. Moses and Aaron were among His priests, And Samuel was among those who called upon His name; They called upon the LORD, and He answered them. He spoke to them in the cloudy pillar; They kept His testimonies and the ordinance that He gave them.
            
You answered them, O LORD our God; You were to them God-Who-Forgives, Though You took vengeance on their deeds. Exalt the LORD our God, And worship at His holy hill; For the LORD our God is holy. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 100</title>
		<content>Make a joyful shout to the LORD, all you lands! Serve the LORD with gladness; Come before His presence with singing. Know that the LORD, He is God; It is He who has made us, and not we ourselves; We are His people and the sheep of His pasture.
            
Enter into His gates with thanksgiving, And into His courts with praise. Be thankful to Him, and bless His name. For the LORD is good; His mercy is everlasting, And His truth endures to all generations. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 101</title>
		<content>I will sing of mercy and justice; To You, O LORD, I will sing praises. I will behave wisely in a perfect way. Oh, when will You come to me? I will walk within my house with a perfect heart.
            
I will set nothing wicked before my eyes; I hate the work of those who fall away; It shall not cling to me. A perverse heart shall depart from me; I will not know wickedness. Whoever secretly slanders his neighbour, Him I will destroy; The one who has a haughty look and a proud heart, Him I will not endure.
            
My eyes shall be on the faithful of the land, That they may dwell with me; He who walks in a perfect way, He shall serve me. He who works deceit shall not dwell within my house; He who tells lies shall not continue in my presence. Early I will destroy all the wicked of the land, That I may cut off all the evildoers from the city of the LORD. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 110</title>
		<content>The LORD said to my Lord, “Sit at My right hand, Till I make Your enemies Your footstool.” The LORD shall send the rod of Your strength out of Zion. Rule in the midst of Your enemies! Your people shall be volunteers In the day of Your power; In the beauties of holiness, from the womb of the morning, You have the dew of Your youth.
            
The LORD has sworn And will not relent, “You are a priest forever According to the order of Melchizedek.” The Lord is at Your right hand; He shall execute kings in the day of His wrath. He shall judge among the nations, He shall fill the places with dead bodies, He shall execute the heads of many countries. He shall drink of the brook by the wayside; Therefore He shall lift up the head. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 111</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD! I will praise the LORD with my whole heart, In the assembly of the upright and in the congregation. The works of the LORD are great, Studied by all who have pleasure in them. His work is honourable and glorious, And His righteousness endures forever.
            
He has made His wonderful works to be remembered; The LORD is gracious and full of compassion. He has given food to those who fear Him; He will ever be mindful of His covenant. He has declared to His people the power of His works, In giving them the heritage of the nations. The works of His hands are verity and justice; All His precepts are sure.
            
They stand fast forever and ever, And are done in truth and uprightness. He has sent redemption to His people; He has commanded His covenant forever: Holy and awesome is His name. The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom; A good understanding have all those who do His commandments. His praise endures forever. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 112</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD! Blessed is the man who fears the LORD, Who delights greatly in His commandments. His descendants will be mighty on earth; The generation of the upright will be blessed. Wealth and riches will be in his house, And his righteousness endures forever.
            
Unto the upright there arises light in the darkness; He is gracious, and full of compassion, and righteous. A good man deals graciously and lends; He will guide his affairs with discretion. Surely he will never be shaken; The righteous will be in everlasting remembrance. He will not be afraid of evil tidings; His heart is steadfast, trusting in the LORD.
            
His heart is established; He will not be afraid, Until he sees his desire upon his enemies. He has dispersed abroad, He has given to the poor; His righteousness endures forever; His horn will be exalted with honour. The wicked will see it and be grieved; He will gnash his teeth and melt away; The desire of the wicked shall perish. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 113</title>
		<content>Praise the LORD! Praise, O servants of the LORD, Praise the name of the LORD! Blessed be the name of the LORD From this time forth and forevermore! From the rising of the sun to its going down The Lord’s name is to be praised.
            
The LORD is high above all nations, And His glory above the heavens. Who is like the LORD our God, Who dwells on high, Who humbles Himself to behold The things that are in the heavens and in the earth? He raises the poor out of the dust, And lifts the needy out of the rubbish heap, That He may seat him with princes—With the princes of His people. He grants the barren woman a home, Like a joyful mother of children. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 116:1-9</title>
		<content>I love the LORD, because He has heard My voice and my supplications. Because He has inclined His ear to me, Therefore I will call upon Him as long as I live. The pains of death encompassed me, And the pangs of Sheol laid hold of me; I found trouble and sorrow.
            
Then I called upon the name of the LORD: “O LORD, I implore You, deliver my soul!” Gracious is the LORD, and righteous; Yes, our God is merciful. The LORD preserves the simple; I was brought low, and He saved me.
            
Return to your rest, O my soul, For the LORD has dealt bountifully with you. For You have delivered my soul from death, My eyes from tears, And my feet from falling. I will walk before the LORD In the land of the living. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Psalm 116:10-19</title>
		<content>I believed, therefore I spoke, “I am greatly afflicted.” I said in my haste, “All men are liars.” What shall I render to the LORD For all His benefits toward me? I will take up the cup of salvation, And call upon the name of the LORD.
            
I will pay my vows to the LORD Now in the presence of all His people. Precious in the sight of the LORD Is the death of His saints. O LORD, truly I am Your servant; I am Your servant, the son of Your maidservant; You have loosed my bonds.
            
I will offer to You the sacrifice of thanksgiving, And will call upon the name of the LORD. I will pay my vows to the LORD Now in the presence of all His people, In the courts of the Lord’s house, In the midst of you, O Jerusalem. Alleluia.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Gospel</title>
		<content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel according to St. Luke may his blessings be with us all. Amen.
            
And the apostles, when they had returned, told Him all that they had done. And He took them and went aside privately into a deserted place belonging to the city called Bethsaida. But when the multitudes knew it, they followed Him; and He received them and spoke to them about the kingdom of God, and healed those who had need of healing.
            
When the day began to wear away, the twelve came and said to Him, “Send the multitude away, that they may go into the surrounding towns and country, and lodge and get provisions; for we are in a deserted place here.” But He said to them, “You give them something to eat.”
            
And they said, “We have no more than five loaves and two fish, unless we go and buy food for all these people.” For there were about five thousand men. And He said to His disciples, “Make them sit down in groups of fifty.” And they did so, and made them all sit down.
            
Then He took the five loaves and the two fish, and looking up to heaven, He blessed and broke them, and gave them to the disciples to set before the multitude. So they all ate and were filled, and twelve baskets of the leftover fragments were taken up by them.
            
Glory be to God forever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Litanies</title>
		<content>O’ Lord who tasted death in the flesh at the ninth hour for our sake, we the sinners; mortify our carnal senses, O’ Christ our God, and deliver us. Let my supplication draw near You, O’ Lord. Give me understanding, according to Your wisdom. Let my request reach Your presence and give me life through Your word.
            
Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Ke agiyou epnevmaty.
            
At the ninth hour You surrendered Your soul to the hands of the Father, after being hanged on the cross. You guided the thief to join You in paradise, do soul, enlighten my mind and let me partake of the grace of Your sacraments so that when I taste Your goodness, I offer You praise unceasingly, longing for Your light above all things O’ Christ our Lord, save us.
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
            
You were born of the virgin, for our sake and endured crucifixion, O’ Righteous Lord, with Your death You defeated death, with Your resurrection You made eternal life manifest. Do not turn Your face from those whom You made by Your hands. Show Your love to mankind O’ Good Lord. Accept the supplications of Your virgin mother on our behalf. O’ Saviour, spare Your humble people and do not let us perish, do not revoke Your promise and do not deprive us of Your mercy for the sake of Your beloved Abraham, your servant Issac and Israel Your saint.
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton Eonon. Amen.
            
When the thief saw the giver of life hanging on the cross, he said; “Had not the one crucified with us being the incarnate God, the sun would not have hidden its light, nor would the earth have quaked in fear. Remember me Almighty Lord when You come into Your Kingdom”.
            
Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Keagiyou ep-nevmaty.
            
O’ Righteous Lord who received the confession of the thief on the cross, accept us who deserve the judgement of death because of our sins. We join him in acknowledging our sins and in confessing Your divinity saying: “Lord remember us when You come into Your Kingdom”.
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
            
When the mother saw the Lamb, the Shepherd and Saviour of the world hanging on the cross, she wept and said: “The world rejoices at the acceptance of salvation, but my heart burns when I look at your crucifixion which You endured for the sake of all; O’ My Son and My God”.
            
Lord have mercy (Kir-ye ley-son) 41 times.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>Holy, Holy, Holy</title>
		<content>Holy, Holy, Holy is the Lord of hosts. Heaven and earth are full of Your glory and honour. God the Father Almighty, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity have mercy upon us. O’ Lord, God of hosts, be with us, for we have no other supporter in our tribulations and adversities but You. O’ God, absolve, remit and forgive us our sins which we have done willingly and unwillingly, and those which we committed knowingly and unknowingly, the hidden and the visible.
            
O’ Lord forgive us for the sake of Your Holy Name that is called upon us, and according to Your mercy and not to our sins.
            
“Our Father, who art in heaven ...”</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Absolution</title>
		<content>O’ God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, who through His appearance You saved us from slavery of the enemy. We ask You, in His blessed and glorious name, to raise our minds above worldly care and bodily desires to the remembrance of Your heavenly commandments.
            
Fulfil Your love to humanity O’ God. Receive our prayers at all times and this prayer of the ninth hour. Grant us to be worthy of Your calling and when we are released from this body, may we be counted among those who kneel before Your throne and are worthy of the sufferings of Your Only Begotten Son, our Lord Jesus Christ.
            
Grant us Your mercy, forgive us our sins and save us with the hosts of saints who sincerely pleased You ever since the beginning. Lord cast away from us the power of the adversary and his evil hosts who were trodden by the power of the cross of Your Only Begotten Son. Accept us O’ Lord Jesus Christ as You accepted the thief on the cross.
            
Shine unto us the light which You gave to those who were in the darkness of Hades. Restore us all to paradise for You are blessed together with Your Father and the Holy Spirit, and worthy of glory, honour, might and obedience now and forever. Amen.</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer>
		<title>The Concluding Prayer</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon us O’ God, have mercy upon us. For You are always worshipped and glorified in heaven and on earth.
            
O’ Christ, our good Lord, plenteous in patience, mercy and compassion, who loves the just and shows mercy to all sinners amongst whom I am the first. Who does not wish death for the sinner but repentance and life, calling us all to salvation for the promised forthcoming rewards. O’ Lord, accept our prayers of this hour and every hour.
            
Ease our lives, and guide us to act according to Your commandments. Sanctify our souls, purify our bodies, set right our thoughts, cleanse our intentions, heal our sickness, forgive us our sins and deliver us from every evil grief and distress. Surround us with Your Holy angels that we may be guided and guarded with them to attain the unity of faith and knowledge of Your imperceptible and infinite glory, for You are blessed for ever. Amen. </content>
	</prayer> 
</hour>  