<hour> 
	<info> 
		<hourName>The Third Hour</hourName> 
		<description>Instituted to commemorate the hour at which our Lord Jesus Christ was condemned. Also, at this hour the Holy Spirit came down on the disciples.</description>
		</info> 
		
	<prayer>
		<title>Introductory Prayer</title>
		<content>† In the name of the Father, and the Son, and the Holy Spirit, one God. Amen.
            
† Lord have mercy, Lord have mercy, Lord bless us. Amen.
            
† Glory be to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit, now and forever and ever. Amen.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>The Lord's Prayer</title>
		<content>O’ Lord make us worthy to pray thankfully:
            
Our Father, who art in heaven, hallowed be Thy Name. Thy Kingdom come. Thy will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. Give us this day our daily bread, and forgive us our trespasses, as we forgive those who trespass against us; and lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through Jesus Christ, our Lord, for Thine is the Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory forever. Amen.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>The Thanksgiving Prayer</title>
		<content>Let us give thanks to the gracious and merciful God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, for He has protected, assisted, preserved and accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.
            
Let us also ask Him the Almighty God, to keep us in peace this blessed day, and all the days of our life. O Lord, Master and Almighty God, the Father of our Lord, God and Saviour Jesus Christ, we thank You on every occasion, in every condition and for all things, for You have protected, assisted, preserved, accepted us, had compassion upon us, supported us and brought us till this hour.
            
Therefore, we ask and appeal to Your goodness, O Lover-of-mankind that You grant us to conclude this blessed day and all the days of our life in peace and in Your fear. All envy, all temptation, all works of Satan, all intrigues of the wicked; rising up of enemies, seen and unseen; do cast away from us and all your people, and from this Holy place.
            
Grant us the endowments and benefactions, as You have given us the authority to trample on serpents and scorpions, and over all the power of the enemy. Lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil, through the grace, mercy and love of mankind of Your only begotten Son, our Lord God and Saviour, Jesus Christ. Glory, honour, dominion and worship are due to You together with Him and the Life-Giving and consubstantial Holy Spirit, now and forever. Amen.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 51</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon me, O God, According to Your loving-kindness; According to the multitude of Your tender mercies, Blot out my transgressions. Wash from my sin. For I acknowledge my transgressions, And my sin is ever before me. Against You, You only, have I sinned, And done this evil in Your sight—That You may be found just when You speak,And blameless when You judge.
            
Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity, And in sin my mother conceived me. Behold, You desire truth in the inward parts, And in the hidden part You will make me to know wisdom. Purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean; Wash me, and I shall be whiter than snow. Make me to hear joy and gladness, That the bones which You have broken may rejoice. Hide Your face from my sins, And blot out all my iniquities.
            
Create in me a clean heart, O God, And renew a steadfast spirit within me. Do not cast me away from Your presence, And do not take Your Holy Spirit from me. Restore to me the joy of Your salvation, And uphold me with Your generous Spirit. Then I will teach transgressors Your ways, And sinners shall be converted to You. Deliver me from bloodguiltiness, O God, The God of my salvation, And my tongue shall sing aloud of Your righteousness.  O Lord, open my lips, And my mouth shall show forth Your praise. For You do not desire sacrifice, or else I would give it; You do not delight in burnt offering.
            
The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit, A broken and a contrite heart—These, O God, You will not despise. Do good in Your good pleasure to Zion; Build the walls of Jerusalem. Then You shall be pleased with the sacrifices of righteousness, With burnt offering and whole burnt offering; Then they shall offer bulls on Your altar. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Introduction</title>
		<content>The Prayer of the Third Hour of this blessed day is offered to Christ my King and my God, beseeching Him to forgive my sins.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 20</title>
		<content>May the LORD answer you in the day of trouble; May the name of the God of Jacob defend you; May He send you help from the sanctuary, And strengthen you out of Zion; May He remember all your offerings, And accept your burnt sacrifice.
            
May He grant you according to your heart’s desire, And fulfil all your purpose. We will rejoice in your salvation, And in the name of our God we will set up our banners! May the LORD fulfil all your petitions. Now I know that the LORD saves His anointed; He will answer him from His holy heaven With the saving strength of His right hand.
            
Some trust in chariots, and some in horses; But we will remember the name of the LORD our God. They have bowed down and fallen; But we have risen and stand upright. Save, LORD! May the King answer us when we call. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
        <title>Psalm 23</title>
		<content>The LORD is my shepherd; I shall not want. He makes me to lie down in green pastures; He leads me beside the still waters. He restores my soul; He leads me in the paths of righteousness For His name’s sake.
            
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil; For You are with me; Your rod and Your staff, they comfort me. You prepare a table before me in the presence of my enemies; You anoint my head with oil; My cup runs over.
            
Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me All the days of my life; And I will dwell in the house of the LORD Forever. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 24</title>
		<content>The earth is the Lord’s, and all its fullness, The world and those who dwell therein. For He has founded it upon the seas, And established it upon the waters. Who may ascend into the hill of the LORD? Or who may stand in His holy place? He who has clean hands and a pure heart, Who has not lifted up his soul to an idol, Nor sworn deceitfully.
            
He shall receive blessing from the LORD, And righteousness from the God of his salvation. This is Jacob, the generation of those who seek Him, Who seek Your face. Lift up your heads, O you gates! And be lifted up, you everlasting doors! And the King of glory shall come in. Who is this King of glory? The LORD strong and mighty, The LORD mighty in battle.
            
Lift up your heads, O you gates! And lift them up, you everlasting doors! And the King of glory shall come in. Who is this King of glory? The LORD of hosts, He is the King of glory. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 26</title>
		<content>Vindicate me, O LORD, For I have walked in my integrity. I have also trusted in the LORD; I shall not slip. Examine me, O LORD, and prove me; Try my mind and my heart. For Your loving-kindness is before my eyes, And I have walked in Your truth.
            
I have not sat with idolatrous mortals, Nor will I go in with hypocrites. I have hated the congregation of evil-doers, And will not sit with the wicked. I will wash my hands in innocence; So I will go about Your altar, O LORD, That I may proclaim with the voice of thanksgiving, And tell of all Your wondrous works.
            
LORD, I have loved the habitation of Your house, And the place where Your glory dwells. Do not gather my soul together with sinners, Nor my life with bloodthirsty men, In whose hands is a sinister scheme, And whose right hand is full of bribes. But as for me, I will walk in my integrity; Redeem me and be merciful to me. My foot stands in an even place; In the congregations I will bless the LORD. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 29</title>
		<content>Give unto the LORD, O you mighty ones, Give unto the LORD glory and strength. Give unto the LORD the glory due to His name; Worship the LORD in the beauty of holiness. The voice of the LORD is over the waters; The God of glory thunders; The LORD is over many waters.
            
The voice of the LORD is powerful; The voice of the LORD is full of majesty. The voice of the LORD breaks the cedars, Yes, the LORD splinters the cedars of Lebanon. He makes them also skip like a calf, Lebanon and Sirion like a young wild ox. The voice of the LORD divides the flames of fire.
            
The voice of the LORD shakes the wilderness; The LORD shakes the Wilderness of Kadesh. The voice of the LORD makes the deer give birth, And strips the forests bare; And in His temple everyone says, “Glory!” The LORD sat enthroned at the Flood, And the LORD sits as King forever. The LORD will give strength to His people; The LORD will bless His people with peace. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 30</title>
		<content>I will extol You, O LORD, for You have lifted me up, And have not let my foes rejoice over me. O LORD my God, I cried out to You, And You have healed me. O LORD, You have brought my soul up from the grave; You have kept me alive, that I should not go down to the pit. Sing praise to the LORD, You His holy name.
            
For His anger is but for a moment, His favour is for life; Weeping may endure for a night, But joy comes in the morning. Now in my prosperity I said, “I shall never be moved.” LORD, by Your favour You have made my mountain stand strong; You hid Your face, and I was troubled. I cried out to You, O LORD; And to the LORD I made supplication: “What profit is there in my blood, When I go down to the pit? Will the dust praise You? Will it declare Your truth? Hear, O LORD, and have mercy on me; LORD, be my helper!”
            
You have turned for me my mourning into dancing; You have put off my sackcloth and clothed me with gladness, To the end that my glory may sing praise to You and not be silent. O LORD my God, I will give thanks to You forever. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 34</title>
		<content>I will bless the LORD at all times; His praise shall continually be in my mouth. My soul shall make its boast in the LORD; The humble shall hear of it and be glad. Oh, magnify the LORD with me, And let us exalt His name together. I sought the LORD, and He heard me, And delivered me from all my fears. They looked to Him and were radiant, And their faces were not ashamed.
            
This poor man cried out, and the LORD heard him, And saved him out of all his troubles. The angel of the LORD encamps all around those who fear Him, And delivers them. Oh, taste and see that the LORD is good; Blessed is the man who trusts in Him! Oh, fear the LORD, you His saints! There is no want to those who fear Him. The young lions lack and suffer hunger; But those who seek the LORD shall not lack any good thing. Come, you children, listen to me; I will teach you the fear of the LORD.
            
Who is the man who desires life, And loves many days, that he may see good? Keep your tongue from evil, And your lips from speaking guile. Depart from evil, and do good; Seek peace, and pursue it. The eyes of the LORD are on the righteous, And His ears are open to their cry. The face of the LORD is against those who do evil, To cut off the remembrance of them from the earth.
            
The righteous cry out, and the LORD hears, And delivers them out of all their troubles. The LORD is near to those who have a broken heart, And saves such as have a contrite spirit. Many are the afflictions of the righteous, But the LORD delivers him out of them all.
            
He guards all his bones; Not one of them is broken. Evil shall slay the wicked, And those who hate the righteous shall be condemned. The LORD redeems the soul of His servants, And none of those who trust in Him shall be condemned. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 41</title>
		<content>Blessed is he who considers the poor; The LORD will deliver him in time of trouble. The LORD will preserve him and keep him alive, And he will be blessed on the earth; You will not deliver him to the will of his enemies. The LORD will strengthen him on his bed of illness; You will sustain him on his sickbed.
            
I said, “LORD, be merciful to me; Heal my soul, for I have sinned against You.” My enemies speak evil of me: “When will he die, and his name perish?” And if he comes to see me, he speaks vain words; His heart gathers iniquity to itself; When he goes out, he tells it. All who hate me whisper together against me; Against me they devise my hurt.
            
An evil disease,“ they say, ”clings to him. And now that he lies down, he will rise up no more.“ Even my own familiar friend in whom I trusted, Who ate my bread, Has lifted up his heel against me. But You, O LORD, be merciful to me, and raise me up, That I may repay them.
            
By this I know that You are well pleased with me, Because my enemy does not triumph over me. As for me, You uphold me in my integrity, And set me before Your face forever. Blessed be the LORD God of Israel From everlasting to everlasting! Amen and Amen.” Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 43</title>
		<content>Vindicate me, O God, And plead my cause against an ungodly nation; Oh, deliver me from the deceitful and unjust man! For You are the God of my strength; Why do You cast me off? Why do I go mourning because of the oppression of the enemy? Oh, send out Your light and Your truth! Let them lead me; Let them bring me to Your holy hill And to Your tabernacle.
            
Then I will go to the altar of God, To God my exceeding joy; And on the harp I will praise You, O God, my God. Why are you cast down, O my soul? And why are you disquieted within me? Hope in God; For I shall yet praise Him, The help of my countenance and my God. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 45</title>
		<content>My heart is overflowing with a good theme; I recite my composition concerning the King; My tongue is the pen of a ready writer. You are fairer than the sons of men; Grace is poured upon Your lips; Therefore God has blessed You forever. Gird Your sword upon Your thigh, O Mighty One, With Your glory and Your majesty.
            
And in Your majesty ride prosperously because of truth, humility, and righteousness; And Your right hand shall teach You awesome things. Your arrows are sharp in the heart of the King’s enemies; The peoples fall under You. Your throne, O God, is forever and ever; A sceptre of righteousness is the sceptre of Your kingdom. You love righteousness and hate wickedness; Therefore God, Your God, has anointed You With the oil of gladness more than Your companions.
            
All Your garments are scented with myrrh and aloes and cassia, Out of the ivory palaces, by which they have made You glad. Kings’ daughters are among Your honourable women; At Your right hand stands the queen in gold from Ophir. Listen, O daughter, Consider and incline your ear; Forget your own people also, and your father’s house; So the King will greatly desire your beauty; Because He is your Lord, worship Him.
            
And the daughter of Tyre will be there with a gift; The rich among the people will seek your favour. The royal daughter is all glorious within the palace; Her clothing is woven with gold. She shall be brought to the King in robes of many colours; The virgins, her companions who follow her, shall be brought to You.
            
With gladness and rejoicing they shall be brought; They shall enter the King’s palace. Instead of Your fathers shall be Your sons, Whom You shall make princes in all the earth. I will make Your name to be remembered in all generations; Therefore the people shall praise You forever and ever. Alleluia
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 46</title>
		<content>God is our refuge and strength, A very present help in trouble. Therefore we will not fear, Though the earth be removed, And though the mountains be carried into the midst of the sea; Though its waters roar and be troubled, Though the mountains shake with its swelling.
            
There is a river whose streams shall make glad the city of God, The holy place of the tabernacle of the Most High. God is in the midst of her, she shall not be moved; God shall help her, just at the break of dawn. The nations raged, the kingdoms were moved; He uttered His voice, the earth melted. The LORD of hosts is with us; The God of Jacob is our refuge.
            
Come, behold the works of the LORD, Who has made desolations in the earth. He makes wars cease to the end of the earth; He breaks the bow and cuts the spear in two; He burns the chariot in the fire. Be still, and know that I am God; I will be exalted among the nations, I will be exalted in the earth! The LORD of hosts is with us; The God of Jacob is our refuge. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Psalm 47</title>
		<content>Oh, clap your hands, all you peoples! Shout to God with the voice of triumph! For the LORD Most High is awesome; He is a great King over all the earth. He will subdue the peoples under us, And the nations under our feet.
            
He will choose our inheritance for us, The excellence of Jacob whom He loves. God has gone up with a shout, The LORD with the sound of a trumpet. Sing praises to God, sing praises! Sing praises to our King, sing praises! For God is the King of all the earth; Sing praises with understanding.
            
God reigns over the nations; God sits on His holy throne. The princes of the people have gathered together, The people of the God of Abraham. For the shields of the earth belong to God; He is greatly exalted. Alleluia.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>The Gospel (John 14:26-15:4)</title>
		<content>A chapter from the Holy Gospel according to St. John may his blessings be with us all. Amen.
            
“But the Helper, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in My name, He will teach you all things, and bring to your remembrance all things that I said to you. “Peace I leave with you, My peace I give to you; not as the world gives do I give to you. Let not your heart be troubled, neither let it be afraid.
            
“You have heard Me say to you, ‘I am going away and coming back to you.’ If you loved Me, you would rejoice because I said, ‘I am going to the Father,’ for My Father is greater than I. “And now I have told you before it comes, that when it does come to pass, you may believe. “I will no longer talk much with you, for the ruler of this world is coming, and he has nothing in Me. “But that the world may know that I love the Father, and as the Father gave Me commandment, so I do. Arise, let us go from here. “I am the true vine, and My Father is the vinedresser.
            
“Every branch in Me that does not bear fruit He takes away; and every branch that bears fruit He prunes, that it may bear more fruit. “You are already clean because of the word which I have spoken to you. “Abide in me, and I in you.
            
Glory be to God forever. Amen.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>The Litanies</title>
		<content>O’ Good Lord, do not take Your Holy Spirit away from us, this which You sent upon Your holy disciples and honourable apostles at the third hour. Create a pure heart in me, O’ God and put a new and loyal Spirit within me, do not banish me from Your presence and do not take Your Holy Spirit from me.
            
Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty.
            
O’ Lord, who sent Your Holy Spirit upon the holy disciples and honourable apostles at the third hour, do not take this away from us, O righteous Lord. We ask You our Lord Jesus Christ, the Son of God the Logos, renew with in us a right and life giving spirit, a filial spirit of chastity, holiness, justice and authority. Our Almighty God, the light of our souls, illuminating every person who comes into this world, have mercy upon us.
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
            
            
Mother of God, full of grace, you are the true vine that carries the fruit of life. We ask you and all the apostles to pray for the salvation of our souls. Blessed be the Lord our God whom we praise each day, because He prepares our path as He is the God of our salvation.
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
            
O’ Heavenly King, the Spirit of truth, the comforter, who is every where and fills everybody. You are the treasure of goodness and giver of life, we ask You to graciously come and dwell with in us, purify us from iniquity and save our souls.
            
Thok-sa-patri Ke ey-you Ke agiyou ep-nevmaty.
            
            
Lord, abide with us as You did with the apostles, when You gave them Your peace, we ask You to grant us Your peace, our Saviour; save us and spare our souls.            
            
Ke-neen Ke-a-ee Ke-is-touse E-onas ton E-onon. Amen.
            
Whenever we stand in Your Holy Temple, we are considered as those who abide in heaven. O’ Mother of God, you are the gate of heaven, open to us the door of mercy.
            
Lord have mercy. (Kir-ye ley-son) 41 times.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>Holy, Holy, Holy</title>
		<content>Holy, Holy, Holy is the Lord of hosts. Heaven and earth are full of Your glory and honour. God the Father Almighty, have mercy upon us.
            
O’ Holy Trinity have mercy upon us. O’ Lord, God of hosts, be with us, for we have no other supporter in our tribulations and adversities but You. O’ God, absolve, remit and forgive us our sins which we have done willingly and unwillingly, and those which we committed knowingly and unknowingly, the hidden and the visible.
            
O’ Lord forgive us for the sake of Your Holy Name that is called upon us, and according to Your mercy and not to our sins.
            
“Our Father, who art in heaven ...”
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>The Absolution</title>
		<content>O’ God of all mercies and Lord of all comfort, at all times, You bring us comfort with Your Holy Spirit. We give You thanks for raising us up for prayer at this holy hour. At this hour You poured the rich grace of Your Holy Spirit in the shape of tongues of fire on Your blessed and honourable disciples.
            
We ask You, O’ Lover of mankind to accept our prayers, forgive our sins and bestow on us the grace of Your Holy Spirit. Purify us from the iniquities of the body and soul, lead us to a spiritual life so that we may seek righteousness and make us worthy to serve You with purity and goodness, through all the days of our lives, for You are worthy of glory, honour and power with the Holy Spirit now and forever. Amen.
		</content>
	</prayer>  
	
	<prayer> 
	<title>The Concluding Prayer</title>
		<content>Have mercy upon us O’ God, have mercy upon us. For You are always worshipped and glorified in heaven and on earth.
            
O’ Christ, our good Lord, plenteous in patience, mercy and compassion, who loves the just and shows mercy to all sinners amongst whom I am the first. Who does not wish death for the sinner but repentance and life, calling us all to salvation for the promised forthcoming rewards. O’ Lord, accept our prayers of this hour and every hour.
            
Ease our lives, and guide us to act according to Your commandments. Sanctify our souls, purify our bodies, set right our thoughts, cleanse our intentions, heal our sickness, forgive us our sins and deliver us from every evil grief and distress. Surround us with Your Holy angels that we may be guided and guarded with them to attain the unity of faith and knowledge of Your imperceptible and infinite glory, for You are blessed for ever. Amen.
		</content> 
	</prayer> 
</hour>  